<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Tech Hamlet]]></title>
  <link href="http://techhamlet.com/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://techhamlet.com/"/>
  <link href="http://techhamlet.superfeedr.com/" rel="hub"/>
  <updated>2014-01-05T10:37:04+05:30</updated>
  <id>http://techhamlet.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Pubudu Kodikara]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Best and the Worst Sri Lankan Computer Stores of 2013]]></title>
    <link href="http://techhamlet.com/2014/01/sri-lankan-computer-stores-2013/"/>
    <updated>2014-01-05T08:40:00+05:30</updated>
    <id>http://techhamlet.com/2014/01/sri-lankan-computer-stores-2013</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>In Sri Lanka its a bit hard to find a good shop to buy tech stuff. People mostly visit Colombo to buy Computers, Laptops and other gadgets&#8230; There are a lot of cheap stores out there&#8230; Many sell crap. You can find the same product elsewhere but the inside is different.  Some sellers deal with cheap crappy manufacturers. Many don&#8217;t give a good after sale service. If you go for warranty there&#8217;s a good chance you&#8217;ll come back empty handed! So how can we avoid these issues and get what we want? Let me help&#8230; In this post I&#8217;m going to list some popular shops in SL and review them&#8230; I can write only about the shops that I have visited. So, if you want to add to the list, please leave a comment!</p>

<p><img src="http://techhamlet.com/images/post-images/2014/01/shop.jpg" alt="Computer Store" /></p>

<h2><a href="http://www.barclays.lk/">Barclays (Excellent)</a></h2>

<p>The first place goes to Barclays. They are well known for their quality and good after sales support. Sometimes you can find the same product for a cheaper price in another shop from a different manufacturer. Trust me&#8230; You don&#8217;t want to go for the cheap one. There&#8217;s a reason why Barclays stay away from some manufacturers. It&#8217;s because they are faulty! Their after sales support is also really good. But not perfect because they still don&#8217;t know how to smile at the customer (I&#8217;m talking about after sales support)</p>

<h2><a href="http://mcentre.lk/">Metropolitan (Excellent)</a></h2>

<p>My experience with Metropolitan is good&#8230; But I still recommend them. They know really well how to handle the customers. Both sales and after sales. You can&#8217;t find more friendlier people than these guys in any other store. They always respond with a smile even when you go for warranty several times! I really like that place. If you need to buy a laptop, a desktop (a branded one), quality accessories, a good phone&#8230; You can visit them. They are the Acer agents in Si Lanka. I think they also directly deal with Sony. I went there first to buy a laptop. But on the first day it started to show a lot of trouble. We can&#8217;t blame Metropolitan because the real problem is with the manufacturer&#8230; HP.  Every machine in that model was faulty. I wrote about this issues once and told everyone to <a href="http://techhamlet.com/2013/03/stay-away-from-hp/">stay away from HP products</a>. Metropolitan handled the case really well&#8230; Got the machine back and returned my money with a smile. You should try them first!</p>

<h2><a href="http://www.epsi.lk/">Epsi (Good)</a></h2>

<p>I don&#8217;t know about their after sales support because I didn&#8217;t got a chance to get that support.  I bought a laptop and a motherboard from them and still didn&#8217;t face any issues! They are the agents for Asus so if you need to buy a really solid laptop that can last long, go for them. They also do Apple products! So, Apple lovers&#8230; go for Epsi.</p>

<h2><a href="http://laptop.lk/">Laptop.lk (Not Good)</a></h2>

<p>They say they are the best place to buy a laptop in Sri Lanka but I say stay away from them at all costs. Laptop.lk have a really good selection. I don&#8217;t think you&#8217;ll need to fear about changed parts because once I bought a HP laptop from them and the HP people accepted the machine for warranty.  They won&#8217;t accept it if the parts are changed.  The problem is with the after sales support. They&#8217;ll tell you to go to that floor then the other floor and finally they&#8217;ll tell you to go and meet the manufacturer! Stay away from them!</p>

<h2><a href="http://www.techinfo.lk/techzone.html">TechZone (Bad)</a></h2>

<p>They might be good for small things like keyboards and mice but they have a bad reputation when it comes to big products. My experience with them is not good&#8230; Once I tried to buy a graphic card. I bought it from these guys. As soon as I install the drivers for the card it started to scream like hell. I contacted the manufacturer online and they said it&#8217;s faulty.  The shop didn&#8217;t believe me. It was really hard to take my money back but finally I did.</p>

<p>And I should say this&#8230; TechZone&#8217;s after sales support team is horrible. I think I went their at about 9.30 AM. All the other shops are open. These guys are just opening.  One man checked my graphic card and asked me to wait till another guy come to work. It was way past 10.00 AM when that guy arrived. He again told me to wait till they fetch another similar card and the guy who just came to work just wondered off the office with his phone&#8230; After a long time the guy who went to fetch the card came back but the guy who test it is out (wondered off)! I had to spend several hours waiting to get my job done and by the time I&#8217;m done, I&#8217;m fully exhausted! I had one question&#8230; Does the managers really pay these guys to wonder off at work hours ignoring the customers? They hardly do any work!</p>

<p>People also complain In forums saying these guys replace laptop parts with cheap ones. The manufacturer won&#8217;t give you any warranty for them. I don&#8217;t know whether this is true so please note it&#8230; Earlier they said they were authorized dealers of HP but HP made an announcement in a local newspaper saying these guys are lying! But now I think they have registered with HP. I would stay away from them at all costs!</p>

<h3>The list is not finished!</h3>

<p>This list is not complete. I wrote only about the shops that I have tried. So, readers&#8230; you have to complete the rest. Write about your favorite shop or about the most horrible place you have ever visited in the comments below!</p>

<h3>Final words&#8230;</h3>

<p>Even though you visit the top vendors in this list, don&#8217;t let them make the selection for you. We can trust the vendors but not all the manufacturers they deal with. So do your research online, check reviews, pick the product you want to buy and then go and buy it. If the product is something small like a mouse or a keyboard, you can get it from anywhere you want! Always be-careful!</p>

<p><em>-Top image source : <a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/lemon/33224803/">Chris Enns</a></em></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Drippler : The Best Way to Learn All About Your Android Device!]]></title>
    <link href="http://techhamlet.com/2014/01/drippler/"/>
    <updated>2014-01-02T17:58:00+05:30</updated>
    <id>http://techhamlet.com/2014/01/drippler</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>If you have an Android device, trust me when I say this&#8230; You still have a lot to learn about your little device! Android is not like any other smart phone OS. It&#8217;s full of cool features. There are a lot of cool apps for you to discover&#8230; Everyday something new and exiting happen in the Android community which you should know! So, how to keep track of all these things?</p>

<p>There are many news reading apps for <a href="http://techhamlet.com/categories/android/">Android</a> but <a href="http://drippler.com/">Drippler</a> is different. It only give you Android stuff! It will give  you top Android news everyday&#8230; Top or newly discovered cool Android apps for you to try&#8230; Articles with tips and tricks&#8230; And many more&#8230;</p>

<p><img src="http://techhamlet.com/images/post-images/2014/01/drippler-shot.jpg" alt="Drippler" /></p>

<p>On the first run, Drippler will detect your device and let you change it if it&#8217;s wrong. So, thereafter you will get most of the stuff targeting your own device!</p>

<p>Drippler is unique. It&#8217;s not built as another news reading app. It&#8217;s soul purpose is to help you discover more about your device and the Android world. The tech world is changing every second so you should have an app like this to keep up with it!</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[SLT Will Increase Download Limits in 2014! But There's Some Bad News!]]></title>
    <link href="http://techhamlet.com/2014/01/new-slt-packages-for-2014/"/>
    <updated>2014-01-02T10:25:00+05:30</updated>
    <id>http://techhamlet.com/2014/01/new-slt-packages-for-2014</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>If you are living in <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Sri_Lanka">Sri Lanka</a> just like me, most probably you might be using Sri Lanka Telecom&#8217;s broadband services. If you do, here&#8217;s some good news for you&#8230; Starting from January 1 2014, <strong>SLT will add extra GBs to your broadband package!</strong> Now that&#8217;s big news! A big gift from SLT! Here are the new package details :</p>

<p><img src="http://techhamlet.com/images/post-images/2014/01/slt-new-packages.jpg" alt="SLT's New Packages" /></p>

<p>If you are an existing customer, you should get these new additions automatically.  You don&#8217;t have to do anything! Great isn&#8217;t it? Hold on&#8230; I said there&#8217;s bad news&#8230; So whats the bad news?</p>

<p><a href="http://www.slt.lk/">SLT</a> is giving some extra GBs but there&#8217;s a catch. .. There&#8217;s always a catch! Earlier, in their package descriptions they mentioned about separate off peak and peak download limits. For example, if they say you are going to get 35 GB per month, it will be 25 GB for peak hours and 10 GB for off peak hours. Earlier, this didn&#8217;t work. For both peak and off peak we got 35 GB. But now things are going to change&#8230;</p>

<p>Now, the peak and off peak limits will be calculated separately! So in the new packages, you will get your old bandwidth limits for peak hours. <strong>The extra GBs will be for off peak!</strong> If you run out of your peak limit, your connection will be slowed down to 64 Kbps during the peak hours. Same theory will be applied for off peak. There&#8217;s one good thing&#8230; Earlier, the off peak time is from 12 AM to 6 AM. That&#8217;s ridiculous. Most of us are sleeping at that time and we will never use the off peak bandwidth. But now, they have extended this time to 8 AM! That&#8217;s really good. But still for businesses this won&#8217;t help. Most people open at 8 AM.</p>

<p>There&#8217;s another small problem&#8230; Did you notice the new and improved usage monitor of SLT? It&#8217;s a really good move. But it also have a catch&#8230; Earlier, smart people used to wait till the end of the month and start downloading everything they need because the usage meter takes some time to update and when it updates, we have already downloaded way over the limit! But I don&#8217;t think it will work now&#8230; <strong>The new usage meter seems to be updating almost instantly :(</strong></p>

<p>Its OK to limits bandwidth like this because I have seen how people download. In Sri Lanka there&#8217;s no law to limit torrenting. So people fill their hard drives with films and games. They buy more drives just for downloads! Thats crazy! The ISPs don&#8217;t have a chance here. But what I&#8217;m saying is that the limits they have added now are too much. Im a web developer and when compared to other countries, I have to pay a huge amount of money to get enough bandwidth for my day today work!</p>

<p>So, just because Sri Lanka Telecom gave you extra GBs to download, don&#8217;t go and download like crazy
&#8230; We know who they are&#8230; SLT won&#8217;t give something without a hidden catch&#8230; You already know that it have the worst reputation in the country. .. So be careful!</p>

<p><strong>Update :</strong> Please note that I didn&#8217;t tell anyone to bend the rules. Im saying not to do it because many people used to skip the rules and go over the limits. But Im telling everyone to stop because (yes its not right) you can&#8217;t do it anymore! I didn&#8217;t even said the new changes are good <strong>A big gift from SLT</strong> and I ment it! Apart from the changes they mention, there are some things that you people need to know and thats why I wrote this post.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Wish You all a Very Happy New Year! How Did You Spent it?]]></title>
    <link href="http://techhamlet.com/2014/01/happy-new-year-2014/"/>
    <updated>2014-01-01T18:18:00+05:30</updated>
    <id>http://techhamlet.com/2014/01/happy-new-year-2014</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>We have just left 2013 and now stepping into 2014! Its a new year. Everyone have their own unique way to celebrate the new year. Make sure you spend it in a meaningful way&#8230;</p>

<p><img src="http://techhamlet.com/images/post-images/2014/01/new-year-2014.jpg" alt="Happy New Year" /></p>

<p>You know what&#8230; Here&#8217;s what I did for the new year&#8230; On the 31st of December, I took my phone, went to the balcony and started making a list&#8230;</p>

<p><a href="http://instagram.com/p/iVYZPaKogx/"><img src="http://techhamlet.com/images/post-images/2014/01/my-balcony.jpg" alt="Thats my Balcony!" /></a></p>

<p>I listed all the mistakes I made in 2013. I wrote down how I am going to fix them! Then I set some goals for the upcoming year. When I&#8217;m done with the review, I went to bed!  In the morning, I woke up like a new born baby&#8230; I wanted to forget about the past and face the new year with a refreshed mind! You should not bring the past junk to the new year. Leave it behind. Only bring what you learnt from the past year. Make sure the new year is better than the past year!</p>

<p>What do you think? Isn&#8217;t it a good way to face the new year? How did you spend it? Share with us!</p>

<p>We are now stepping into a brand new year&#8230; So, what kind of posts do you want from us this year? Let us know what you want and we shall give it to you!</p>

<h1>Happy New Year Everyone!</h1>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Amazon is Going to Deliver Your Packages using Drones... Or Rockets!]]></title>
    <link href="http://techhamlet.com/2013/12/amazon-drones-and-rockets/"/>
    <updated>2013-12-08T18:48:00+05:30</updated>
    <id>http://techhamlet.com/2013/12/amazon-drones-and-rockets</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Recently Amazon made an announcements about their latest delivery method. Drones! That&#8217;s right&#8230; Drones&#8230; Small unmanned air crafts! Most of you might heard of middle East drone killings. Well Amazon will not use those drones! Phew&#8230;</p>

<iframe width="640" height="360" src="http://techhamlet.com//www.youtube.com/embed/98BIu9dpwHU" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen></iframe>


<p>Amazon&#8217;s main target is to deliver the goods faster than ever. Why? The biggest issue that make the normal delivery times long and totally unpredictable is traffic! No matter wherever you live, some one have to use the public roads to reach you. You&#8217;ll never know how long will it take to reach you. But drones are coming from above. No traffic jams no crazy pedestrians no cops&#8230; They have the sky for themselves!</p>

<p>But drones are not always the best method. If you think about weather they are totally unpredictable. If Amazon is going to use small drones as shown in their video they are going to face a big problem. I&#8217;m not sure how they will face harsh weather conditions. You don&#8217;t want your package to get lost in a storm aren&#8217;t you? There&#8217;s another problem&#8230;. If we get used to drones hovering over our heads, it will give terrorist groups a good excuse to use their own drones to have a peak inside the white house! A major security issue! Another problem&#8230; You can&#8217;t say there&#8217;s no traffic at all&#8230; What about thousands of manned aircrafts flying everyday? OK they fly in a very high altitude so the drones won&#8217;t meet them unless they decide to pass an airport! The other traffic issue come from birds! Rarely birds hit air crafts and take them down completely (like the famous <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/US_Airways_Flight_1549">Hudson river crash</a>). But when they climb to their cruising altitude they are safe. But drones might not go that high. So there&#8217;s a big threat from nature!</p>

<p>Drones have their advantages and disadvantages. Hope Amazon have considered about all the issues before they made the announcement. Let&#8217;s put these drones aside for a sec. What do you think about rocket delivery? They can be faster than drones! See for yourself :</p>

<iframe width="640" height="360" src="http://techhamlet.com//www.youtube.com/embed/jHrngvEok9M" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen></iframe>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Ubuntu Won't Detect My Nvidia GPU! How To Install Proprietary Driver? ]]></title>
    <link href="http://techhamlet.com/2013/12/ubuntu-wont-detect-nvidia/"/>
    <updated>2013-12-08T18:10:00+05:30</updated>
    <id>http://techhamlet.com/2013/12/ubuntu-wont-detect-nvidia</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I just bought a new GT640 Nvidia card. I&#8217;m running the latest Ubuntu 13.10.  So I thought it will detect my new GPU without any issues. The system booted up and worked fine but unfortunately it didn&#8217;t detect the card to let me install proprietary Nvidia drivers. So, can we install proper drivers without Ubuntu&#8217;s support?</p>

<p><img src="http://techhamlet.com/images/post-images/2013/12/nvidia.jpg" alt="Nvidia" /></p>

<p>Its easy. But first of all, you need to make sure that you have an Nvidia card on your machine. I&#8217;m serious! We are going to add <a href="https://launchpad.net/~xorg-edgers/+archive/ppa">xorg-edgers ppa</a> and install the latest Nvidia graphic drivers. Since these are new and still considered as testing, there&#8217;s a slight chance of breaking things. So, be careful ! I&#8217;m using these drivers and they work just fine for me! So let&#8217;s get started&#8230;</p>

<ul>
<li>First add the xorg-edgers ppa and update the sources with the following command :</li>
</ul>


<figure class='code'><div class="highlight"><table><tr><td class="gutter"><pre class="line-numbers"><span class='line-number'>1</span>
<span class='line-number'>2</span>
</pre></td><td class='code'><pre><code class=''><span class='line'>sudo add-apt-repository ppa:xorg-edgers/ppa
</span><span class='line'>sudo apt-get update</span></code></pre></td></tr></table></div></figure>


<ul>
<li>Next upgrade your system to make sure everything is up-to-date (The new PPA might have some updated xorg packages):</li>
</ul>


<figure class='code'><div class="highlight"><table><tr><td class="gutter"><pre class="line-numbers"><span class='line-number'>1</span>
</pre></td><td class='code'><pre><code class=''><span class='line'>sudo apt-get dist-upgrade</span></code></pre></td></tr></table></div></figure>


<ul>
<li>Finally install the latest drivers :</li>
</ul>


<figure class='code'><div class="highlight"><table><tr><td class="gutter"><pre class="line-numbers"><span class='line-number'>1</span>
</pre></td><td class='code'><pre><code class=''><span class='line'>sudo apt-get install nvidia-331</span></code></pre></td></tr></table></div></figure>


<p>If you run into any issues. You can simply remove the proprietary drivers with the following commands :</p>

<figure class='code'><div class="highlight"><table><tr><td class="gutter"><pre class="line-numbers"><span class='line-number'>1</span>
<span class='line-number'>2</span>
<span class='line-number'>3</span>
<span class='line-number'>4</span>
</pre></td><td class='code'><pre><code class=''><span class='line'>sudo apt-get remove nvidia-331
</span><span class='line'>sudo apt-get autoremove
</span><span class='line'>sudo apt-get install ppa-purge
</span><span class='line'>sudo ppa-purge xorg-edgers</span></code></pre></td></tr></table></div></figure>


<p>Still, if you need to try proprietary drivers even if the latest one failed, you can try installing the old packages that come with Ubuntu :</p>

<figure class='code'><div class="highlight"><table><tr><td class="gutter"><pre class="line-numbers"><span class='line-number'>1</span>
</pre></td><td class='code'><pre><code class=''><span class='line'>sudo apt-get install nvidia-current</span></code></pre></td></tr></table></div></figure>


<p>If that also failed, here&#8217;s how to remove it :</p>

<figure class='code'><div class="highlight"><table><tr><td class="gutter"><pre class="line-numbers"><span class='line-number'>1</span>
<span class='line-number'>2</span>
</pre></td><td class='code'><pre><code class=''><span class='line'>sudo apt-get remove nvidia-current
</span><span class='line'>sudo apt-get autoremove</span></code></pre></td></tr></table></div></figure>


<p><em>Image source : <a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/djandywdotcom/10641625834">djandyw.com</a></em></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[3 Cool Ubuntu Plymouth (Boot) Themes : OS X, PAW Ubuntu and PAW Gnome]]></title>
    <link href="http://techhamlet.com/2013/09/how-to-install-ubuntu-plymouth-themes/"/>
    <updated>2013-09-04T11:54:00+05:30</updated>
    <id>http://techhamlet.com/2013/09/how-to-install-ubuntu-plymouth-themes</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Ubuntu already have a sleek boot screen. Sometimes you might want to change it to something different. If you are an OS X or a <a href="http://techhamlet.com/categories/windows/">Windows</a> user, you have to put aside your feelings and accept what they give to you. But you are a <a href="http://techhamlet.com/categories/linux/">Linux</a> user&#8230; You can do anything you want! So, why can&#8217;t we change the boot screen into one of these&#8230;?</p>

<p><img src="http://techhamlet.com/images/post-images/2013/09/paw-ubuntu-plymouth-themes.jpg" alt="Ubuntu Plymouth Themes" /></p>

<p>Today I&#8217;m going to show you how to install three simple Plymouth (boot) themes on Ubuntu. You can install most of the other plymouth themes out there in the same way. So, stick with us&#8230;</p>

<h2>First, Download the Plymouth Themes :</h2>

<p><a href="http://ubuntuone.com/1f1cEzkl42YhzBFkUwL3Kg">OS X Plymouth Theme</a></p>

<p><a href="http://love2spooge.deviantart.com/art/PAW-Ubuntu-Plymouth-Theme-173974272">PAW-Ubuntu Plymouth Theme</a></p>

<p><a href="http://gnome-look.org/content/show.php/?content=158162">Ubuntu Gnome Paw Plymouth Theme</a></p>

<h2>Before Installing&#8230;</h2>

<p>Before installing the themes, we need to make sure they will be displayed correctly. For that&#8230;</p>

<ul>
<li>Open the Terminal <code>Ctrl+ALT+T</code> and enter the following commands to create a file called <strong>splash</strong> in <strong>/etc/initramfs-tools/conf.d/</strong> :</li>
</ul>


<figure class='code'><div class="highlight"><table><tr><td class="gutter"><pre class="line-numbers"><span class='line-number'>1</span>
</pre></td><td class='code'><pre><code class=''><span class='line'>sudo gedit /etc/initramfs-tools/conf.d/splash</span></code></pre></td></tr></table></div></figure>


<ul>
<li>Next, place the following line in that file and save it :</li>
</ul>


<figure class='code'><div class="highlight"><table><tr><td class="gutter"><pre class="line-numbers"><span class='line-number'>1</span>
</pre></td><td class='code'><pre><code class=''><span class='line'>FRAMEBUFFER=y</span></code></pre></td></tr></table></div></figure>


<ul>
<li>Now run the following commands to update the system :</li>
</ul>


<figure class='code'><div class="highlight"><table><tr><td class="gutter"><pre class="line-numbers"><span class='line-number'>1</span>
</pre></td><td class='code'><pre><code class=''><span class='line'>sudo update-initramfs -u;sudo update-alternatives --config default.plymouth</span></code></pre></td></tr></table></div></figure>


<h2>How To Install OS X and PAW-Ubuntu themes :</h2>

<ul>
<li>Navigate to the download directory and unzip the downloaded files :</li>
</ul>


<figure class='code'><div class="highlight"><table><tr><td class="gutter"><pre class="line-numbers"><span class='line-number'>1</span>
<span class='line-number'>2</span>
<span class='line-number'>3</span>
</pre></td><td class='code'><pre><code class=''><span class='line'>cd ~/Downloads/
</span><span class='line'>unzip Paw-OSX.zip
</span><span class='line'>unzip PAW_OS_X_Plymouth_Theme_by_love2spooge.zip</span></code></pre></td></tr></table></div></figure>


<ul>
<li>Now move the files to the Plymouth Themes directory :</li>
</ul>


<figure class='code'><div class="highlight"><table><tr><td class="gutter"><pre class="line-numbers"><span class='line-number'>1</span>
<span class='line-number'>2</span>
</pre></td><td class='code'><pre><code class=''><span class='line'>sudo mv Paw-OSX/ /lib/plymouth/themes
</span><span class='line'>sudo mv Paw-Ubuntu/ /lib/plymouth/themes</span></code></pre></td></tr></table></div></figure>


<ul>
<li>Next, install the newly added themes :</li>
</ul>


<figure class='code'><div class="highlight"><table><tr><td class="gutter"><pre class="line-numbers"><span class='line-number'>1</span>
<span class='line-number'>2</span>
</pre></td><td class='code'><pre><code class=''><span class='line'>sudo update-alternatives --install /lib/plymouth/themes/default.plymouth default.plymouth /lib/plymouth/themes/Paw-OSX/paw-osx.plymouth 100
</span><span class='line'>sudo update-alternatives --install /lib/plymouth/themes/default.plymouth default.plymouth /lib/plymouth/themes/Paw-Ubuntu/paw-ubuntu.plymouth 100</span></code></pre></td></tr></table></div></figure>


<ul>
<li>After that, you have to select which plymouth theme you need to use. For that, first issue the following command to bring up the default plymouth chooser :</li>
</ul>


<figure class='code'><div class="highlight"><table><tr><td class="gutter"><pre class="line-numbers"><span class='line-number'>1</span>
</pre></td><td class='code'><pre><code class=''><span class='line'>sudo update-alternatives --config default.plymouth</span></code></pre></td></tr></table></div></figure>


<ul>
<li>Next, enter the number of the plymouth theme you need to use. In my case, its 1 for OS X theme and 3 for PAW-Ubuntu</li>
</ul>


<p><img src="http://techhamlet.com/images/post-images/2013/09/choose-plymouth-theme.jpg" alt="Choose Plymouth Theme" /></p>

<ul>
<li>Finally, enter the following command to update the system :</li>
</ul>


<figure class='code'><div class="highlight"><table><tr><td class="gutter"><pre class="line-numbers"><span class='line-number'>1</span>
</pre></td><td class='code'><pre><code class=''><span class='line'>sudo update-initramfs -u</span></code></pre></td></tr></table></div></figure>


<h2>How To Install PAW Gnome theme :</h2>

<p>Installing this theme is fairly easy. When downloading, you might have noticed that it comes as a .deb file. We just have to install it and select the theme in the plymouth chooser&#8230;</p>

<ul>
<li>First, navigate to the download folder and double click on the <code>158162-plymouth-theme-paw_13.04_all.deb</code> file which you just downloaded and install it</li>
<li>After finishing the installation, open the Terminal <code>Ctrl+ALT+T</code> and enter the following command to open the plymouth chooser :</li>
</ul>


<figure class='code'><div class="highlight"><table><tr><td class="gutter"><pre class="line-numbers"><span class='line-number'>1</span>
</pre></td><td class='code'><pre><code class=''><span class='line'>sudo update-alternatives --config default.plymouth</span></code></pre></td></tr></table></div></figure>


<ul>
<li><p>Next select the number of the <code>/lib/plymouth/themes/paw/paw.plymouth</code> theme. (Refer to the screenshot above. In my case its 4 according to the screenshot)</p></li>
<li><p>Finally, enter the following command to update the system :</p></li>
</ul>


<figure class='code'><div class="highlight"><table><tr><td class="gutter"><pre class="line-numbers"><span class='line-number'>1</span>
</pre></td><td class='code'><pre><code class=''><span class='line'>sudo update-initramfs -u</span></code></pre></td></tr></table></div></figure>


<p>Enjoyed? These are the two popular methods of plymouth theme installation. You can use these methods to install most of the boot themes out there. There were also GUI apps to do this job but they are outdated. But still, it won&#8217;t kill you if you use the Terminal! Common, its better than the GUI apps!</p>

<p><em>- Special thanks should go to <a href="http://www.noobslab.com/2013/05/mac-os-x-theme-for-ubuntu-1304-raring.html">noobslab.com</a> for introducing the OS X splash screen</em></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Killer Android Home Screens : Simple Colors]]></title>
    <link href="http://techhamlet.com/2013/08/simple-colors-android-home/"/>
    <updated>2013-08-15T07:54:00+05:30</updated>
    <id>http://techhamlet.com/2013/08/simple-colors-android-home</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Unlike most of the other mobile operating systems, Android is extremely customizeable. Apple&#8217;s iOS and Microsoft&#8217;s Windows Phone force us to use the look and feel they choose for us. But Android users are free to do anything with their systems! Why? Mainly because Android is a <a href="http://techhamlet.com/categories/linux/">Linux</a> distribution and Linux is free, open and extremely customizeable! So, today we are going to see how to turn your Android Home screen into this :</p>

<p><img src="http://techhamlet.com/images/post-images/2013/08/simple-colors-android-home.jpg" alt="Simple Colors Android Home Screen" /></p>

<p>This is my tab&#8217;s current home screen. For some reason, I liked it so much that I wanted to write a post on how to re-create something like this. First of all, if you are an Android user, you should know that you can customize your system in anyway you want. But you also need to be careful when downloading those <em>super cool</em> apps from the <a href="http://techhamlet.com/categories/android/">Android</a> market (Play Store). Many contain malware!</p>

<h3>So, if you are ready, here are the apps I used to customize my Android home screen :</h3>

<ul>
<li><a href="https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.teslacoilsw.launcher">Nova Launcher (free)</a></li>
<li><a href="https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.launchertheme.kxnt.click">Click UI (Go Apex Nova theme)</a></li>
<li><a href="https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=in.vineetsirohi.customwidget">Ultimate custom widget (UCCW)</a></li>
<li><a href="https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.tung91.uccw.typoclock">UCCW - Typo Clock</a></li>
</ul>


<p><strong>Nova Launcher</strong> is one of the most popular custom Android launchers out there. Its fast, stable and extremely customizeable. Many people use the Nova Launcher <em>Prime</em> (The paid version) for extensive customizations. But in here, the free version is more than enough. The <strong>Click UI</strong> icon theme is one of the most beautiful icon designs I have ever seen. It have a small price on it&#8230; $1! But I think its fair. The <strong>UCCW</strong> app is really cool. It can be used to build awesome custom widgets for your home screen. If you can&#8217;t create one, there are many custom build widgets for UCCW that will blow your mind. The <strong>Typo Clock</strong> is one of those cool custom widgets.</p>

<p>Now I have shown you the tools. How you customize your screen is completely up-to you. One thing&#8230; If you need to customize icons in the side dock, press hold an icon and click edit. Then click on that icon and select an icon from the big list. Click UI have 550+ HD icons! So, you might be able to get a custom icon for almost all your apps.</p>

<p>When creating the new <a href="http://techhamlet.com/2013/08/techhamlet-15/">Tech Hamlet 15.0</a>, I created a special category for Android. Earlier it was hidden. Now I&#8217;m going to write more and more Android posts. If you like customization posts like this, please leave a comment and I might write more!</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Elementary OS Luna is Released! Fast, Beautiful, Clean and its Linux!]]></title>
    <link href="http://techhamlet.com/2013/08/elementary-os-luna/"/>
    <updated>2013-08-14T21:04:00+05:30</updated>
    <id>http://techhamlet.com/2013/08/elementary-os-luna</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>After nearly 2 years of development, they have just released the final stable version of Elementary OS Luna ! Its main aim is to build a more beautiful, elegant, consistent, fast, and a stable Linux operating system. I think they have succeeded! Many Linux fans waited anxiously for the release of Elementary OS Luna&#8230;</p>

<p><img src="http://techhamlet.com/images/post-images/2013/08/elementary-os-luna.jpg" alt="My Elementary OS Luna Desktop" /></p>

<h2>Its built on Ubuntu 12.04!</h2>

<p>Elementary team built Luna on Ubuntu 12.04. Why 12.04 and not the latest 13.04? The 12.04 version of Ubuntu is the LTS version. LTS (Long Term Support) releases are the most stable releases of Ubuntu and they are supported for a very long time than the others. Others are considered as experimental builds used by the developers to test new features. The Elementary OS team wanted to make their OS extremely stable. So, they picked <a href="http://techhamlet.com/2012/04/things-to-do-after-installing-ubuntu-12-04-the-start/">Ubuntu 12.04</a>. This will make them very stable but it also have a down side! Ubuntu 12.04 was released on April 2012. Its older than a year and it have pretty old software. Those software receive security updates and bug fixes. But no new features.</p>

<h2>It is really fast&#8230;</h2>

<iframe width="640" height="480" src="http://techhamlet.com//www.youtube.com/embed/3kvmyDR7FCo?rel=0" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen></iframe>


<p>See? How fast it can get? This is only a beta version. The latest stable version they just released is much better. Elementary team have done a lot of optimizations to bring up the speeds. They did this by their own code and by using several programs like <code>preload</code>. Preload will load your most used programs into the memory so they will load quickly. But there&#8217;s a catch&#8230; Sometimes your previous work will or will not be saved. The browser might sometimes keep your previous settings but the Terminal sometimes loose them. It even loose the history and the preferences. But you can simply disable preload and things will still work fast!</p>

<h2>Elementary OS Luna have custom built apps&#8230;</h2>

<p>They have a lot of custom built apps to replace the existing ones. For example, there&#8217;s no Gedit, they use their own app Scratch for note editing. They use their own shell Pantheon, their own dock Plank which is based on Docky, their own settings panel Switchboard, Wing Panel as the top panel, Pantheon Greeter will replace the login screen, their own Pantheon file manager and many more&#8230; These custom apps are more lighter than their counterparts. But sometimes they might lack some important features that we are used to. For example, I like clean and simple apps. Elementary OS Luna &#8216;s text editor is also elegant and I like it. But still it doesn&#8217;t have the features I need and I went back to Sublime. I also like their music app Music (Formerly Noise) but I went back to Clementine. But most of the other apps are really cool. Because they are so good, some of them have been already ported to work on other distributions like <a href="http://techhamlet.com/2012/03/install-arch-linux-on-your-machine/">Arch</a> and on latest versions of Ubuntu.</p>

<h2>Great consistent design and a guide for developers on how to keep the consistency!</h2>

<p>Elementary OS Luna have a very consistent design. I think its even better than Apple&#8217;s consistency (I&#8217;m not saying Apple have better looks. <a href="http://techhamlet.com/2013/06/mac-os-x-vs-linux/">Mac have old looks</a>). The Elementary team doesn&#8217;t stop there&#8230; They also want every one who build apps for their OS to follow their designs. They have special guidelines for developers on how to make their user interfaces. But the problem is, many people won&#8217;t develop apps specifically for Elementary. Its not that popular yet and there are many more popular <a href="http://techhamlet.com/categories/linux/">Linux</a> distributions they have to pass. If they come to the top, their guideline might become a standard. Even without that I think its a good idea if all major Linux distributions get together and define a specific set of UI guidelines. Things are scattered in Linux. Elementary OS Luna is a very good start!</p>

<h2>Less customizeability&#8230;</h2>

<p>Luna is well built and have a very good design. Some people won&#8217;t need anything beyond it. But some need customization. If we doesn&#8217;t want customizations and want the same old look, feel, ways, we all might use Mac. But Linux is meant for adventurous people who need innovation and a system built for their own tastes. But Elementary OS Luna is a bit less customizeable. No many settings to change things. You can use the conf editors (<code>dconf</code> or <code>gconf</code>) but its not enough. Elementary is not completely like Mac. Even though they restrict customization, they encourage third-party plugins to do this job. I think its not bad. But since the OS is still new, there are no many plugins available. I think it might be solved soon.</p>

<h2>Final thoughts&#8230;</h2>

<iframe width="640" height="360" src="http://techhamlet.com//www.youtube.com/embed/pWoo4xv-qoA?rel=0" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen></iframe>


<p>Elementary OS Luna is a great OS and its a new beginning. A new branch in Linux. Many Linux branches focus on areas like Security, Stability, Being Bleeding edge, Customizeability, etc&#8230; But less people have done so much for the UI&#8230; The design&#8230; Linux is not a developer only OS. Even the most novice users use it because its more user friendly than any other OS in the planet. But many distros doesn&#8217;t focus on them. Elementary OS Luna is built for both developers and novice users. Out-of the box you&#8217;ll get what you want. A developer also need an out of the box solution sometimes. Many need them because they don&#8217;t have time to custom build their systems. They need something that work. Not to spend time hacking! You can hack Elementary OS if you want to&#8230; There&#8217;s no restriction. So I think its suited for everyone! Here&#8217;s a quick roundup of Elementary OS Luna :</p>

<p><strong>Pros :</strong></p>

<ul>
<li>Great design (Clean, Beautiful, etc)</li>
<li>Consistent</li>
<li>Fast</li>
<li>Stable</li>
<li>Easy to use and learn</li>
<li>Extremely user friendly</li>
</ul>


<p><strong>Cons :</strong></p>

<ul>
<li>Old packages (But you are free to use PPAs to get latest versions)</li>
<li>Less customizeable</li>
<li>Some annoying default settings like no desktop icons, single click to open files and no minimize button (All can be fixed)</li>
</ul>


<p>Impressed? Then try it, head over to <a href="http://elementaryos.org/">Elementary</a> website and download the stable ISO. Don&#8217;t let the website fool you. It might show a price tag but its only a donation tag. You can get the OS for free. If you like Elementary OS Luna , leave a comment below and if the demand is good, I might write some tutorials for it!</p>

<p><strong>I think you must watch this Elementary review created by <a href="http://www.youtube.com/user/OhHeyItsLou?feature=watch">Lou</a> :</strong></p>

<iframe width="640" height="360" src="http://techhamlet.com//www.youtube.com/embed/_cia_8OVESA?rel=0" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen></iframe>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Get High Quality Font Rendering in Linux with Infinality!]]></title>
    <link href="http://techhamlet.com/2013/08/infinality-linux-font-rendering/"/>
    <updated>2013-08-07T20:52:00+05:30</updated>
    <id>http://techhamlet.com/2013/08/infinality-linux-font-rendering</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Several years ago when I was trying Linux for the first time, I faced a hard time staring at the default system fonts. When compare to Windows, they were ugly! I even tried installing Windows fonts on Linux and replacing the default system fonts with the exact same versions used in Windows. But still it looked bad! Then I fiddled with other font settings like font Hinting, Aliasing&#8230; But nothing helped! Why? The problem is not with the fonts, its with the font rendering!</p>

<p><img src="http://techhamlet.com/images/post-images/2013/08/fonts.jpg" alt="Fonts" /></p>

<p>Our operating systems use a separate module to render fonts. Its duty is to get the font file and display it to the user. In many Linux distributions, by default the system doesn&#8217;t handle font rendering well. We see jagged low quality fonts. If you are coming from Windows, you&#8217;ll clearly see the difference. If you are coming from Mac, you&#8217;ll know the difference on the first look! Mac and Windows have very good font rendering systems and.. Linux have solutions for almost any problem!</p>

<p>If you are using Ubuntu or any other distribution base on Ubuntu (like Linux Mint and Elementary OS), you won&#8217;t feel the difference. Ubuntu apply their own patches to the default font rendering system so their fonts look extremely good. But if you want to improve it further or if you are coming from another Linux distribution, here&#8217;s a solution&#8230;</p>

<h2>Infinality &#8230;</h2>

<p><a href="http://www.infinality.net/blog/">Infinality</a> is a set of patches made to improve freetype2 font rendering in Linux. It automatically adjust settings like hinting and subpixel rendering to give the best quality fonts for you.</p>

<blockquote><p>The purpose of these patches is to freely provide the nicest font rendering of any operating system. The second goal is to provide customization so that the end user is able to adjust the settings to his or her taste.</p></blockquote>

<h2>How to install Infinality &#8230;</h2>

<h3>On Arch Linux :</h3>

<ul>
<li>Make sure you have <a href="https://wiki.archlinux.org/index.php/Yaourt">Yaourt</a> installed</li>
<li>Next install Infinality with the following commands :</li>
</ul>


<figure class='code'><div class="highlight"><table><tr><td class="gutter"><pre class="line-numbers"><span class='line-number'>1</span>
<span class='line-number'>2</span>
</pre></td><td class='code'><pre><code class=''><span class='line'>sudo yaourt freetype2-git-infinality
</span><span class='line'>sudo yaourt fontconfig-infinality-git</span></code></pre></td></tr></table></div></figure>


<p>**If you have a 64bit system, you also have to install this :</p>

<figure class='code'><div class="highlight"><table><tr><td class="gutter"><pre class="line-numbers"><span class='line-number'>1</span>
</pre></td><td class='code'><pre><code class=''><span class='line'>sudo yaourt lib32-freetype2-git-infinality</span></code></pre></td></tr></table></div></figure>


<ul>
<li>Finally, use this command to choose what style you need (choose from debug, Linux, OSx2, OSx, Win98, WinXP, Win7 and Infinality) :</li>
</ul>


<figure class='code'><div class="highlight"><table><tr><td class="gutter"><pre class="line-numbers"><span class='line-number'>1</span>
</pre></td><td class='code'><pre><code class=''><span class='line'>sudo infctl setstyle</span></code></pre></td></tr></table></div></figure>


<h3>On Ubuntu :</h3>

<ul>
<li>You can install Infinality in Ubuntu with these commands :</li>
</ul>


<figure class='code'><div class="highlight"><table><tr><td class="gutter"><pre class="line-numbers"><span class='line-number'>1</span>
<span class='line-number'>2</span>
<span class='line-number'>3</span>
<span class='line-number'>4</span>
</pre></td><td class='code'><pre><code class=''><span class='line'>sudo add-apt-repository ppa:no1wantdthisname/ppa
</span><span class='line'>sudo apt-get update
</span><span class='line'>sudo apt-get upgrade
</span><span class='line'>sudo apt-get install fontconfig-infinality</span></code></pre></td></tr></table></div></figure>


<ul>
<li>Finally, use this command to select a style :</li>
</ul>


<figure class='code'><div class="highlight"><table><tr><td class="gutter"><pre class="line-numbers"><span class='line-number'>1</span>
</pre></td><td class='code'><pre><code class=''><span class='line'>sudo bash /etc/fonts/infinality/infctl.sh setstyle</span></code></pre></td></tr></table></div></figure>


<h3>On Fedora :</h3>

<ul>
<li>You can find instructions on how to install these patches in Fedora on this <a href="http://www.infinality.net/forum/viewtopic.php?f=2&amp;t=77">page</a></li>
</ul>


<h3>On Debian :</h3>

<ul>
<li>Here are the instructions <a href="http://forums.debian.net/viewtopic.php?f=16&amp;t=88545">for Debian</a></li>
</ul>


<h3>On all systems&#8230;</h3>

<ul>
<li>After you are done installing, log off and login for the changes to take effect.</li>
</ul>


<p>Did it work? If not, please let us know!</p>

<p><em><strong>Image Source :</strong></em> <a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/tarale/2897185492/">Taryn</a></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Tech Hamlet 15 : No WordPress! Faster... Clean.. And Much Better!]]></title>
    <link href="http://techhamlet.com/2013/08/techhamlet-15/"/>
    <updated>2013-08-04T21:40:00+05:30</updated>
    <id>http://techhamlet.com/2013/08/techhamlet-15</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>After a very long time of inactivity, we are coming back again! Everyone&#8230; Say hello to Tech Hamlet 15.0! This not just a simple redesign&#8230; The platform have changed&#8230;  The server have changed&#8230;  The policies have changed&#8230;  The way we work have changed&#8230; The layout have changed
&#8230; What we write have changed&#8230;  The design have changed&#8230;  The core code have changed&#8230;  Everything have changed in Tech Hamlet!</p>

<p><img src="http://techhamlet.com/images/post-images/2013/08/techhamlet-15.jpg" alt="Tech Hamlet 15" /></p>

<h2>Problems with the old site :</h2>

<ul>
<li><p><strong>WordPress</strong> : Yep&#8230;  <a href="http://wordpress.org/">WordPress</a> became a problem to us! Its one of the most popular and the most powerful blogging platforms on earth.  But its getting too heavy.  There are a lot of unwanted features.  We can&#8217;t  blame WordPress.  Now that platform is used for a lot of applications.  It&#8217;s not just a blogging platform.  Now it&#8217;s used for blogging, marketing sites, portfolios, and as a CMS for many different kinds of sites. It&#8217;s a mess. Unless you do a full optimization of the server,  the theme and the WordPress core itself,  you might have to spend a huge amount of money to find a good host for it. That&#8217;s the same thing that happened to me. A Web site need to load really fast.  But WordPress have a lot of code to be generated before showing the site to the user. It&#8217;s a big problem!</p></li>
<li><p><strong>Ads</strong> : The first major problem we had is with Advertisements and Paid links! That&#8217;s what drive most of the blogging community. People sell links and place ads on their websites without focusing on the contents. I hated this. But I also had to sell links and ads to keep the blog running.  I spent a lot of money for the host because I wanted to make things a lot faster. But recently I did a small survey and found out that a lot of people hate ads.  They draw the attention of the users.  That&#8217;s what we want.  But that&#8217;s not what our readers want.  They come here for valuable content.  Not for ads. Selling links is the other problem. Too many links = bad SEO. We even received a penalty from good old Google!</p></li>
<li><p><strong>Guest posts</strong> : You will be amazed to see how many guest posts we receive. It always give me head aches when trying to go through all these emails. Sometimes, Tech Hamlet publish many irrelevant guest posts than relevant articles from us. Most of the guest posts we receive are off topic and doesn&#8217;t even make sense! With them, we get links. A lot of linking from the guest posts. This is also a major reason that made Google award us a cool penalty!</p></li>
<li><p><strong>Clutter</strong> : The old Tech Hamlet had too much clutter. A lot of sidebar widgets, a lot of bits and pieces in a post page. All of them steal away the reader&#8217;s attention. That&#8217;s not good. It started as a simple design but later turned into a cluttered porcupine!</p></li>
<li><p><strong>The design and the layout</strong> : I made that old design and it looked really good to me. But there were some problems. Too much white in the design made it hard for some people to read. The font is not good. Actually every-time I tried to put a completely new design, WordPress stopped me. Its hard to change the WordPress layout. We can do it but it will be reverted back to defaults when we update. That&#8217;s not good. The other problem with the design is that its old. Many blogs have already upgraded to modern designs!</p></li>
<li><p><strong>Categories</strong> : Most of the categories were added back in 2009. I wanted to add as much categories as I can but later it turned out to be a disaster. If we use a wider category model, then it only keep growing. We had to add more categories and it became a bit out of control! Categories should simply tell the reader what we have. But our categories told them that we are making a fruit salad!</p></li>
<li><p><strong>WordPress plugins and speed</strong> : In order to get the right functionality, I had to add a lot of plugins. Several times I tried to prune the plugins but that list never shrieked. Those plugins and the dynamic nature of WordPress made the blog slow. That will make the readers sad too!</p></li>
<li><p><strong>Hosting</strong> : If I need to pay for WordPress hosting, then I need a lot of ads and get my hands dirty. The site need a very powerful server so I had to spend a lot for a good VPS.</p></li>
</ul>


<h2>Our solutions :</h2>

<h3>No more WordPress ! Hello Octopress !</h3>

<p><img src="http://techhamlet.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/06/octopress-550x385.jpg" alt="Octopress" /></p>

<p>WordPress is dead. We have just moved away from that platform to Octopress. Its all about static blogging. The <a href="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</a> framework is built on Jekyll and Ruby. The source code for the website resides in your machine and in a remote git repository (if you need backups). There&#8217;s a default minimal and responsive design added by Octopress. But you are free to change it. I have done a lot of customization to the default Octopress layout. You can&#8217;t say its a Octopress site by just looking at it! I have added the following features to make it more powerful :</p>

<ul>
<li>Featured images for posts. Every post will have a <code>fimage</code> tag. The site will pull the image path from this tag and use it to display a post image in the index and in the sidebar recent posts.</li>
<li>Featured posts. If the <code>featured</code> tag is set to true in a post, the blog index will style that post differently. (For example, add a bigger image to it)</li>
<li>Auto excerpts. Octopress have excerpts. The only thing is you have to add the <code>&lt;!--more--&gt;</code> tag manually. I imported nearly 1,500 posts from my old WordPress setup. I can&#8217;t go through all these posts and add the more tag manually! So, I used the <code>truncatewords</code> method in Liquid Templates like this :</li>
</ul>


<figure class='code'><div class="highlight"><table><tr><td class="gutter"><pre class="line-numbers"><span class='line-number'>1</span>
</pre></td><td class='code'><pre><code class=''><span class='line'>post.content | strip_html | truncatewords: 30</span></code></pre></td></tr></table></div></figure>


<ul>
<li>One of the best things about Octopress is that you can get free hosting on Github. But there&#8217;s a problem&#8230; If you upload the source to Github (Free account), anyone can get your posts easily (Thats what I think. Im not sure). You can push the source to a different place like Bitbucket. But it won&#8217;t make the source open. So, I pushed the posts, pages and their images to my private repository in Bitbucket and left the source in Github. This bring another problem. You need to push the source, pages, posts and images separately to their own origins which can become a big headache. But, I created two scripts to <strong>commit</strong> and <strong>push</strong>. To take care of all the repositories from one script. I will write about it in <a href="http://techhamlet.com/">Tech Hamlet</a> in the near future. (They are not included in the source).</li>
<li>Auto generated open graph meta tags for each and every page</li>
<li>And there are some more tiny things I added&#8230;</li>
</ul>


<p>If you want to use these features on your own site, you can check the <a href="https://github.com/TechHamlet/TechHamlet.github.io">source code of Tech Hamlet</a>. Now its open sourced!</p>

<p>After you setup the layouts, you are ready to go. Then you write the posts. After that, with two commands, Octopress will generate a static HTML version of your site and automatically push it to the server. You are done! In the future, I will write some posts about Octopress so you also can follow. Because its static HTML, Tech Hamlet is now a lot faster than before. The web server doesn&#8217;t have to generate any heavy php before sending it to you. Its already built.</p>

<h3>Almost NO ADS!</h3>

<p>Tech Hamlet 15.0 doesn&#8217;t have any adsense ads&#8230; No links will be sold from both the blogroll and from posts. We will only have two 125x125 ads in the sidebar. Only two small ads for the whole site. It will be enough to keep the ship afloat. It will also please our readers. No ads mean less clutter. Now things are more organized and clean. When designing the previous versions of Tech Hamlet, first it looked like a very nice design. But after I inserted the ads to the template I got sad :( . They made everything look ugly. There&#8217;s no way I can tell what ad Google will place on my site. So it posed a major problem. Now we don&#8217;t have them! Cool isn&#8217;t it?</p>

<h3>No more irrelevant guest posts</h3>

<p>The <a href="http://techhamlet.com/contact/">guest posts rules</a> are tightened. If you are here just to get a link to your product or to get a link for your client, no matter how much money you are willing to pay, we won&#8217;t accept your gust post. If you are willing to write a quality article that is related to our site, we will let you write. We will also let you link to your own blog. Not to a product. People who link to products mostly write rubbish!</p>

<h3>No more clutter!</h3>

<p>Many things have been removed from the site. There&#8217;s nothing much in the sidebar. Its cleaned. The post pages are also clean. No big author bios and multiple social share buttons. You can find three popular share buttons at the bottom. That&#8217;s all!</p>

<h3>A more cleaner and a unique design&#8230;</h3>

<p>Unlike WordPress, the Octopress layout can be easily changed. I did a lot of customization to the default layout and then added my own theme. I tried to make something unique. For example, the way I added the category links in the header is a bit crazy. But I think it will work.</p>

<h3>Less categories&#8230;</h3>

<p>As I mentioned before, adding more categories made the site look like a fruit salad. But now I have reduced it to 5. 5 main categories to group every thing. Now our goal is clear. Its not a fruit salad any more!</p>

<h3>Hosting</h3>

<p>Since I use Octopress and generate a static HTML site, I can get free hosting on <a href="https://github.com">Github</a>! Some people doesn&#8217;t go for free hosting because most of those hosting providers cannot be trusted and some even put ads on our sites. But Github is the world&#8217;s number one source code host! Millions of developers use it every day. So, there&#8217;s no question about their quality. Both the source code and the website can be hosted in Github.</p>

<h3>There are more&#8230;</h3>

<p>Apart from that, there are more changes to our site. For example, we will now reduce the amount of news posts we add. There are a lot of websites out there which does the job better than us. So, if there&#8217;s some big news topic, then I&#8217;ll write about it. Mostly, we will focus on tutorials and reviews.</p>

<p>Earlier, our markup didn&#8217;t pass W3 validations. Even-though I managed to make the site&#8217;s design W3 valid, after adding WordPress plugins, the validations failed. But now, the site is W3 valid!</p>

<p>Today we placed a big milestone for our blog. Many things have changed and will be changed in the future. I didn&#8217;t got time and interest to update the blog in the past few weeks. I&#8217;m turning into a developer. Octopress is extremely developer friendly. It use the tools we use every day like Git and Markdown. I like it! First I converted my other site <a href="http://youarecurio.us/">YouAreCurio.us</a> into Octopress and immediately felt its power.</p>

<p>I think Tech Hamlet will have a very bight future with these new changes. In a way, we have joined the open source developer community! Cool! So, what do you think about our new changes? Please let us know as comments below&#8230;</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Bitdefender 2014 is Released! Its Faster, Lighter and More Secure!]]></title>
    <link href="http://techhamlet.com/2013/06/bitdefender-2014-released/"/>
    <updated>2013-06-26T21:22:14+05:30</updated>
    <id>http://techhamlet.com/2013/06/bitdefender-2014-released</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="http://techhamlet.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/06/bitdefender2014-550x385.jpg" alt="Bitdefender 2014" /> Bitdefender 2014</p>

<p>Folks at Bitdefender have just released a major upgrade to their security suits! The new Bitdefender 2014 is now available for everyone! Bitdefender started to test this new version a bit earlier than in the previous years. They released the first <a href="http://techhamlet.com/2013/03/bitdefender-2014-beta/">public beta</a> version on March. After testing for about 4 months, they have just released the new security suit today.</p>

<h3>Bitdefender 2014&#8230;</h3>

<p><a href="http://www.bitdefender.com/solutions/internet-security.html">Bitdefender 2014</a> &#8216;s main point is speed. According to Bitdefender, their new photon technology will make things a lot lighter. That means, the anti virus will be a lot faster! Not only the anti virus, even the whole system will be faster. Normally, an anti virus can significantly slow down a computer. Some people don&#8217;t even use anti virus apps for this reason. But with this new technology, Bitdefender 2014 might change the way how people think about security suits.</p>

<p>Apart from the speed, there are a lot of security enhancements, enhancements to<a href="http://techhamlet.com/2013/06/bitdefender-safepay/"> safepay</a>, cloud anti spam and some new features. The developers have also changed the look and feel of the app. Now its even more smoother. Will glide through your system smoothly protecting every corner of it!</p>

<p>Currently, according to independent lab tests, Bitdefender is the number one security suit on the planet. If you read of blog earlier, you should know this. That&#8217;s why we always follow their products. Recently, they have also gained the crown in Android security which was earlier held by Trust Go. Now, if you already have Bitdefender, you can install this new version free of charge. If you want to buy it, please wait. We might hold a free giveaway of Bitdefender 2014 ! Want to grab a free key to this awesome security suit? Just be patient and wait&#8230; Also if you need to learn more on this new Bitdefender, wait for my full review.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[A better understanding of Software as a Service]]></title>
    <link href="http://techhamlet.com/2013/06/a-better-understanding-of-software-as-a-service/"/>
    <updated>2013-06-26T10:23:50+05:30</updated>
    <id>http://techhamlet.com/2013/06/a-better-understanding-of-software-as-a-service</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>For most of us, it&#8217;s easy to think of software as a product. After all, you can purchase it in a shop and, for the most part, it works in a similar fashion.</p>

<p>The truth is, however, that we do not own the software we use. Anything you purchase is not yours. Instead you only own a licence; this is a common business model known as Software as a Service orSaaSfor short.</p>

<p>To help understand this, here&#8217;s a quick look at how this approach actually works and why, in cases where the software is rather important to you or your work, you may want to look into<a href="http://www.nccgroup.com/en/our-services/software-escrow-verification">software escrow</a>to further protect yourself.</p>

<p><img src="http://techhamlet.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/07/app_saas_img2.jpg" alt="Software as a Service" /> Software as a Service</p>

<h3>The License</h3>

<p>At itssimplest, software is typically a licence, not a product. This is why you have to agree and enter into an end user agreement for most software products as this enters you into aSaaSagreement with the software provider.</p>

<p>The drawback to this is that you don&#8217;t have access to the software&#8217;s inner workings or source code. The advantage, however, is that it&#8217;s not up to you to maintain the software. As your only leasing it,itsup to the provider to offer a working product throughout this time. Should that fail to happen, disputes can happen and this is where escrow can become important.</p>

<h3>Verifying perspective</h3>

<p>In any dispute, it&#8217;s easy to get drawn out into a longer disagreement. When you need software fast, such as when you rely or depend upon it for work, this isn&#8217;t the best option. A lot of disagreements come around due to both sides being unable to agree on a solution. Instead, you should look to<a href="http://www.nccgroup.com/en/our-services/software-escrow-verification">escrow</a>to provide a neutral perspective from a legal stand point.</p>

<p>Escrow companies can verify software and make the right actions in accordance with the law. This should keep both sides happy but the simple act of putting the software in escrow ensures that the provider is serious about keeping their product in working order.</p>

<p>In many cases, it can be a simple sign of trust or added security. Developers design their software, as a product, to work, but having the added security layer of escrow support means both sides just want a working product. Should it come to it, the use of escrow will ensure, in cases where the agreement has been broken, you&#8217;re given what you&#8217;re legally entitled to.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Mac OS X vs Linux : What is The Best Windows Alternative? Mac or Linux]]></title>
    <link href="http://techhamlet.com/2013/06/mac-os-x-vs-linux/"/>
    <updated>2013-06-22T19:23:20+05:30</updated>
    <id>http://techhamlet.com/2013/06/mac-os-x-vs-linux</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="http://techhamlet.com/wp-content/uploads/2012/12/update_for_your_computer.jpg" alt="Mac OS X vs Linux" /> Mac OS X vs Linux <em>Image source : <a href="http://www.stickycomics.com/computer-update/">Sticky Comics</a></em></p>

<p>Mac OS X vs Linux, this is not an easy debate. Most of us start with Windows because it&#8217;s the most commonly used OS. But that doesn&#8217;t mean its the best. Many migrate to other alternatives according to their needs. But the recent the Windows 8 release made some users to <a href="http://techhamlet.com/2013/06/windows-8-is-not-user-friendly/">leave Windows</a>. For some its really good but for some it&#8217;s not. Windows now have a problem. So, if you ever decide to ditch Windows, what will you pick? Mac or Linux?</p>

<h3>Why Windows is more popular?</h3>

<p>The biggest reason for Windows&#8217;s popularity is the support from manufacturers! Most of the PCs and Notebooks come with Windows pre-installed! Only an experienced user who have already used a different OS will try to change it. People like Dell and HP have already started to ship Linux pre-installed machines. But still it&#8217;s not enough to beat Windows. Mac also have their own machines. So, they both stay ahead of Linux. Not good forMac OS X vs Linux battle.</p>

<h3>Mac and Linux have some similarities&#8230;</h3>

<p>Mac OS X is based on Unix. They take Unix and add their own GUI to it. GNU/Linux is like Unix but it&#8217;s not Unix. Richard Stalleman wanted to build a free, open sourced and a better system than Unix. So, he built his own system from scratch by looking at Unix. He called it GNU. GNU means,<strong>G</strong>nu<strong>I</strong>s<strong>N</strong>ot<strong>U</strong>nix! After adding the Linux kernel to it, we dropped the word GNU and used Linux. But the OS is GNU.</p>

<h3>They have a lot of differences! So, lets start the debate,Mac OS X vs Linux :</h3>

<h4>Firest of all, Linux is free and open source and Mac OS X is expensive!</h4>

<p>The first reason you might pick Mac over Linux (in the battle of Mac OSX vs Linux) is the price. Mac is expensive. More expensive than Windows. There are many free apps for Windows which might be enough for an average user. But Mac apps are also expensive. You have to pay for most of the stuff!</p>

<p>Mac is completely closed sourced. They take full revenge from those who copy at least a single word from their system. They take patents for every thing including every curve and line in their designs. If anyone copy them, they will go directly to the court.</p>

<p>Linux is completely free. If some one ask to pay you to get a Linux distribution, you can sue him. According to their license, you can&#8217;t sell it and make profits. You can get money for the service you provide, but can&#8217;t make a profit.</p>

<p>The Linux code is completely open sourced. You can get it and customize it in any way you want, add your name to it and distribute it to the world.</p>

<h4>Mac OS X won&#8217;t let you customize their OS&#8230; You can customize every corner of Linux!</h4>

<p>In OS X, you can&#8217;t customize much. You have to do things in their way. Apple will decide how your desktop will look like and how you will work with it. You must obey them. There&#8217;s no other choice! If you are a newbie who don&#8217;t do much with the computer, then OS X will be ok for you!</p>

<p>Linux is open sourced. You can customize every single bit of the OS if you know how to do it. Unlike other operating systems, Linux is built to support third party themes. There are high quality themes that you can use. No hacking needed. It&#8217;s originally supported. You will also get a lot of options. A lot of different desktop environments, Gnome, XFC, Cinnamon, Unity, KDE, etc&#8230; A lot of different themes&#8230; A lot of different gadgets like docks, widgets, desk lets, etc</p>

<h4>Mac OS X vs LinuxPerformance&#8230;</h4>

<p>A recent study have revealed that Ubuntu in a Mac can outperform OS X! Beating OS X in its own grounds! The clear winner is Linux&#8230;</p>

<h4>Ease of use, ease of learning and ease of migrating from Windows&#8230;</h4>

<p>I have tried Mac&#8230; If you are moving from Windows to OS X, you might get into trouble. Some shortcuts might not work, it will scroll in the opposite direction, more weird things will happen&#8230; Linux is also different. It have a lot of differences. But its easy to move from Windows. and its easy to learn.<a href="http://www.youtube.com/user/OsFirstTimer?feature=watch">OsFirstTimer</a> have released several videos on this issues. In these videos, a completely new user will face different operating systems and review them. From the systems she used, she picked Linux as the best :</p>

<h4>Support&#8230;</h4>

<p>When we take support, it&#8217;s a tie. Apple provide a really good support for their products. Linux have a really good support from thousands of people in the community. So, both have good support.</p>

<h4>Security&#8230;</h4>

<p>Earlier Apple said OS X is completely impenetrable. But recently, a mass malware attack took down thousands of Mac users. It&#8217;s not completely secure. Same goes to Linux. No mass malware attack took down Linux but still it&#8217;s not completely secure. It&#8217;s a tie. But both are better than Windows.</p>

<h4>Mac is boring&#8230; No innovation&#8230;</h4>

<p>People say Apple is innovative. Yes they are innovative. They release completely new awesome products. But after the initial release of the product, no major updates. No major features&#8230; No much changes&#8230; The same boring old thing will get minor updates and bug fixes for the rest of its life. Its old stuff. Boring&#8230;</p>

<p>Linux and Windows do complete re-designs occasionally. Linux know how to do their redesigns without killing the user. It have innovation!Mac OS X vs Linux, who is the best?</p>

<h3>What is the most widely used OS?</h3>

<p>You might say its Windows but it&#8217;s not. The most widely used OS is Linux! The mobile world is dominated by Android and Android is a Linux distribution. Almost 90% of web servers run Linux. Many embedded systems have Linux, Super computers run on Linux. Linux is the king&#8230;</p>

<h3>Mac OS X vs Linux&#8230; What is the best?</h3>

<p>Clearly, Linux is the better option. Mac users will fire at me but this is the truth. Many people buy Apple products to show that they are rich. Trust me, that&#8217;s the truth. If not, why spend a lot of money just to buy a boring old product? Their support is extremely good. Is it worth it? Once I tried to buy a new notebook and considered Mac. I was unable to find a powerful enough Mac to replace my existing old notebook! A Mac can&#8217;t replace its power. You might say you&#8217;re going for the OS X. But isn&#8217;t Linux better than OS X? If you want the OS X look, it won&#8217;t take 30 minutes to transform your Linux desktop into a Mac. But you can never transform Mac into a Linux! That&#8217;s the difference! Mac users are trapped inside Apple&#8217;s prison while Linux people are free to do anything! The clear winner in the battle of Mac OS X vs Linuxis Linux!</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Firefox Beats Chrome In Many Ways]]></title>
    <link href="http://techhamlet.com/2013/06/firefox-beats-chrome/"/>
    <updated>2013-06-20T19:34:26+05:30</updated>
    <id>http://techhamlet.com/2013/06/firefox-beats-chrome</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="http://techhamlet.com/wp-content/uploads/2012/05/browser-war-550x385.jpg" alt="Firefox vs Chrome" /> <em>Image Source :<a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/50186930@N00/5948520195/">JUDEE</a></em></p>

<p>Yesterday I had a good chuckle at my friends words &#8216;Chrome never ceases to amaze me&#8217; Personally, I find lots of problems with Google&#8217;s so called wonder browser Chrome and although I do use it sometimes to try new add-ons that sound interesting, I prefer to stick with Firefox.</p>

<p>Here&#8217;s what annoys me most about Chrome: firstly, it uses tons of memory; a lot more, in fact, than Firefox, which people accuse of being slower. Just bring up your Task Manager when you&#8217;re running Chrome to see how many different processes it has open - one for each tab - and how much memory it&#8217;s using. I guarantee you&#8217;ll be surprised.</p>

<p>Secondly, its always crashing and showing that stupid &#8216;He&#8217;s dead Jim&#8217; message as if the inconvenience were supposed to be funny. And you can bet that when your PC hangs on shutdown because a program needs to be closed the culprit is Chrome. LOL.</p>

<p>I also dislike the often scary list of permissions, you need to agree to when installing certain extensions, giving them access to your data on all websites, as well as your tabs, bookmarks and browsing activity. Given Google&#8217;s notoriety for storing personal info, these permissions make me paranoid, no matter how harmless they may be. Firefox add-ons don&#8217;t make these demands so why would Chrome get away with it?</p>

<h3>Firefox vs Chrome, who is the winner?</h3>

<p>If you ask me, Chrome is very overrated, especially compared to more innovative browsers such as Opera, Maxthon and yes Firefox. I also prefer Mozilla&#8217;s non-profit ethos to Google&#8217;s sneaky tax-avoiding tricks, and find bookmarks much easier to manage in Firefox. My friend is entitled to his views, bit look closer at Chrome and you&#8217;ll see the cracks.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Just Moved You Are Curious from Wordpress to Octopress!]]></title>
    <link href="http://techhamlet.com/2013/06/wordpress-to-octopress/"/>
    <updated>2013-06-18T10:53:47+05:30</updated>
    <id>http://techhamlet.com/2013/06/wordpress-to-octopress</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="http://techhamlet.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/06/octopress-550x385.jpg" alt="Octopress" /> Octopress</p>

<p>I always felt Wordpress is too much for me. I wanted something simple, something more customizable and something really fast! So, why not go with Octopress? It&#8217;s a blogging platform that runs on your own machine. It generate static HTML files and upload them to the server. No dynamic content. That means the website is extremely fast! You have a local copy and Git is already used by the framework which you can use to send backups to remote servers like Github and Bitbucket.Its fast, reliable and extremely customizable!</p>

<p>Octopress is a platform built on Jekyll which use Ruby to generate static HTML blogs. You write your posts in Markdown and place them in a separate folder. When generating the website, Octopress will use these markdown files and the layouts you defined to generate your website. Its a bit geeky but you can learn it. Octopress have a very good documentation which will guide you through all the steps. After generating, you just have to push it to the web server. If you need to move to a new server, you don&#8217;t have to run complex scripts and setup databases. Just push to the new address and the website will work.</p>

<p>You might think that we need dynamic stuff for comments. Actually, I already use Disqus. Octopress have built in Disqus integration which can be used for comments. I just moved my site without loosing any of the existing comments!</p>

<p>For hosting, you can use any simple web server. Any server can serve simple static HTML files. You also don&#8217;t need a big server because there are no server-side scripting used in Octopress. You can even host the site in GitHub for free! I used that option. The website&#8217;s code is now open sourced!</p>

<h3>Read more about Octopress &#8230;</h3>

<p>What do you think? Octopress have all the thing I need. No extra stuff to slow down the site. You can read more about Octopress and even enjoy my new site if you go there now :<a href="http://youarecurio.us/2013/06/wordpress-to-octopress/">Moved From Wordpress to Octopress! Simple, Faster and More Reliable!</a></p>

<p>For Tech Hamlet, I have bigger plans! Read that post and see what im planning for Tech Hamlet!</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Bitdefender Safepay : A More Secure Browser for Your Critical Work!]]></title>
    <link href="http://techhamlet.com/2013/06/bitdefender-safepay/"/>
    <updated>2013-06-17T20:41:28+05:30</updated>
    <id>http://techhamlet.com/2013/06/bitdefender-safepay</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="http://techhamlet.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/06/safepay-550x412.jpg" alt="Bitdefender Safepay" /> Bitdefender Safepay</p>

<p>If you are banking online, buying things from an online store or doing other critical stuff like this, many people will try their best to get their hand on your details. Your credit card information, the passwords, user names, emails, these stuff can ruin your life if they go to the wrong hands. But, the problem is, the Internet is full of these hands trying to grab your data. Is there a way to get rid of them? You can&#8217;t get rid of every threat, butBitdefender Safepay will help you stay away from most of them!</p>

<p>Bitdefender is the number one security suit in the industry and they have kept that place for years. Recently, they introduced a cool new feature in their security suit namedBitdefender Safepay. It is a browser. But not an ordinary one. Its more secure. A normal browser doesn&#8217;t enforce all the security features because it will slow down the normal browsing. ButBitdefender Safepay have them enabled.</p>

<p>First of all, it will scan your machine for threats and warn you if there&#8217;s something wrong. If there&#8217;s something that can tap your data and ruin your life. Then, when you deal with online banks, stores and other critical sites, it will secure your whole connection, and the browser environment you are working. It will isolate the browser from the rest of the system and make sure no one can tap into it. It also have a virtual keyboard which can be used to prevent keyloggers from logging your data and sending them to the hackers! Bitdefender Safepay can also protect you from unsecured Wi-Fi connections by securing the whole connection. Normally, if you use an unsecured public hot spot, there are a lot of chances that your data might get hacked. But<a href="http://www.bitdefender.com/media/html/beta-safepay/index.html">Bitdefender Safepay</a> can rescue you.</p>

<p>Bitdefender offered all these cool features as an add-on in their security suit. So, you need to install Bitdefender in order to get this functionality. But Bitdefender doesn&#8217;t want to keep it only for their own customers. They are getting ready to release it to every one! Now even if you don&#8217;t have Bitdefender, you can installBitdefender Safepay Beta and use the highly secured browser for your critical work!</p>

<p>The product is still in beta stage and might have some bugs. But still its worth trying out because the <a href="http://youarecurio.us/2013/05/internet-is-evil/">internet is getting dangerous</a> everyday! Bitdefender have also organized a small contest where they will give fabulous prizes to those who help them test their beta product! Download and tryBitdefender Safepay now!</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Does the iPhone 6 Represent the Future?]]></title>
    <link href="http://techhamlet.com/2013/06/iphone-6-represent-the-future/"/>
    <updated>2013-06-17T20:16:38+05:30</updated>
    <id>http://techhamlet.com/2013/06/iphone-6-represent-the-future</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Although there is still no official word from Apple about the latest iPhone incarnation, several creative individuals continue to come up with some unique design and concept ideas to get the publics imagination racing.</p>

<p>In the past we have seen built-in projectors, virtual laser keyboards and even 3D cameras. However, this latest concept combines technology that is currently available with innovations that every Smartphone manufacturer strives for.</p>

<p><img src="http://techhamlet.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/06/iphone6-550x385.jpg" alt="iPhone 6" /> <em>Image Source :<a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/thronx/8008932080/">thronx</a></em></p>

<h3>Water-resistant and dustproof</h3>

<p>Even though the iPhone 5 has shown itself to be fairly resistant to water in recent consumer tests, this concept takes inspiration from other Smartphones available on the market.</p>

<p>Sony&#8217;sExperiaZ, released in February 2013, has Ingress Protection Ratings of IP55 and IP57, making it dustproof and water-resistant. Able to deal with one metre of water for up to thirty minutes, theExperiaZ is one of the world&#8217;s toughest Smartphones.</p>

<p>Last year, speculation suggested that Apple was working on a water-resistant coating for its products, meaning such protection from the elements would be a distinct possibility. However, with full control over its component supply chain, Apple might be content with the money it makes from repairs.</p>

<h3>Wireless charging</h3>

<p>In what is considered by several commentators to be the holy grail of technological progress, this iPhone 6conceptalso manages to achieve wireless charging.</p>

<p>Even with some great<a href="http://www.buymobilephones.net/mobile-phones/apple">Apple iPhone deals</a>available, messy cables and tangled wires have been one of the most frustrating aspects about owning a Smartphone. Manufacturers including Nokia, LG and HTC have all recently championed the technology, but there has yet to be any solid inductive charging evidence from Apple.</p>

<p>However, when you consider that Samsung&#8217;s Galaxy S4, the iPhone&#8217;s main smartphone rival, now supports wireless charging, it certainly makes sense for Apple to pursue the technology.</p>

<h3>Other notable features</h3>

<p>Additional innovations include touch-sensitive casing and LED notifications, taking influence from some recent Apple patents.</p>

<p>AlthoughLED notifications on either side of the casing isa novel idea, current iPhone users already have this option via the camera&#8217;s flashlight. Up until now, Apple has favoured physical buttons. However, there are various aesthetic and design advantages to touch-sensitive controls.</p>

<p>It remains to be seen whether the iPhone 6 will include these advances. However, with rival Smartphones already featuring such additions, Apple should certainly take note.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Firefox OS to Launch on Foxconn Tablets]]></title>
    <link href="http://techhamlet.com/2013/06/firefox-os-launch-on-foxconn/"/>
    <updated>2013-06-15T20:32:54+05:30</updated>
    <id>http://techhamlet.com/2013/06/firefox-os-launch-on-foxconn</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://techhamlet.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/06/Firefox-OS_tablet_610x416.jpg"><img src="http://techhamlet.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/06/Firefox-OS_tablet_610x416-300x204.jpg" alt="Firefox OS to launch on Foxconn tablets" /></a> Firefox OS to launch on Foxconn tablets</p>

<p>Firefox is ready to launch their OS soon this summer.
<strong>
</strong></p>

<h3><strong>What Happened?</strong></h3>

<p>Browser developer Mozilla and hardware manufacturer Foxconn signed a deal to create devices running open-source mobile OS. Mozilla had already signed up smartphone makers to use its OS on their handsets. Foxconn is a Chinese manufacturer that produces hardware for a host of big tech companies, including Apple.</p>

<p><strong>
</strong></p>

<h3><strong>How will it affect you? The Firefox OS</strong></h3>

<p>This is a big win if you&#8217;re a Firefox fan and could help propel the new operating system onto other devices. This OS focuses on HTML rather than apps, which means for example you can use the Facebook mobile site rather than download an app. It also has strong privacy controls. The Firefox OS tablets will offer a competitive alternative to Google and Apple devices.</p>

<p><strong>
</strong></p>

<h3><strong>What does Techhamlet think about Firefox OS?</strong></h3>

<p>This is Foxconns first big move into making its own branded hardware and that&#8217;s big news for Firefox. We think it will give Mozilla a head start in the Chinese market and could lead to other hardware makers adopting the software.</p>

<blockquote><p>If Foxconn&#8217;s tablets are a success then Firefox OS will be too</p></blockquote>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[BBM Coming To Android]]></title>
    <link href="http://techhamlet.com/2013/06/bbm-coming-to-android/"/>
    <updated>2013-06-15T20:31:42+05:30</updated>
    <id>http://techhamlet.com/2013/06/bbm-coming-to-android</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://techhamlet.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/06/bbm.jpg"><img src="http://techhamlet.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/06/bbm-300x176.jpg" alt="Blackberry Messenger BBM coming to Android this summer" /></a> Blackberry Messenger BBM coming to Android this summer</p>

<blockquote><p>The once venerable messaging service BBM makes its belated move to Android this summer.</p></blockquote>

<p>Blackberry has announced that its flagship BBM will be coming to Android this summer. It will be available as a free download from the Play Store, and will compete with the likes of Google&#8217;s new Hangouts app, Facebook Home and WhatsApp in the battle to dominate the mobile messaging space.</p>

<blockquote><p>The move to make BBM cross platform was first mooted two years ago</p>

<p>It will also be available for iOS</p></blockquote>

<p>Blackberry was the market leader in messaging and ranked among the worlds biggest smartphone manufacturers. Today the company&#8217;s share stands at less than 3% and falling. The same figures put Android&#8217;s share at a whopping 75%.</p>

<p>Messaging is increasingly becoming one of the key battlegrounds in the mobile, and is seen as one of the best ways to lock users into a particular platform. Meanwhile &#8216;over the top&#8217; messaging apps are plentiful. It&#8217;s into this crowded market that BBM is making its move. The brand may be diminished and the decision may appear to be a last resort for Blackberry, but the app and service are still more than competitive and fondly remembered by many of its past users. That should at least guarantee a certain level of interest in the app when it arrives this summer.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
