<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Tech Hamlet]]></title>
  <link href="http://techhamlet.com/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://techhamlet.com/"/>
  <link href="http://techhamlet.superfeedr.com/" rel="hub"/>
  <updated>2013-08-07T21:18:05+05:30</updated>
  <id>http://techhamlet.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Pubudu Kodikara]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Get High Quality Font Rendering in Linux with Infinality!]]></title>
    <link href="http://techhamlet.com/2013/08/infinality-linux-font-rendering/"/>
    <updated>2013-08-07T20:52:00+05:30</updated>
    <id>http://techhamlet.com/2013/08/infinality-linux-font-rendering</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Several years ago when I was trying Linux for the first time, I faced a hard time staring at the default system fonts. When compare to Windows, they were ugly! I even tried installing Windows fonts on Linux and replacing the default system fonts with the exact same versions used in Windows. But still it looked bad! Then I fiddled with other font settings like font Hinting, Aliasing&hellip; But nothing helped! Why? The problem is not with the fonts, its with the font rendering!</p>

<p><img src="http://techhamlet.com/images/post-images/2013/08/fonts.jpg" alt="Fonts" /></p>

<p>Our operating systems use a separate module to render fonts. Its duty is to get the font file and display it to the user. In many Linux distributions, by default the system doesn&rsquo;t handle font rendering well. We see jagged low quality fonts. If you are coming from Windows, you&rsquo;ll clearly see the difference. If you are coming from Mac, you&rsquo;ll know the difference on the first look! Mac and Windows have very good font rendering systems and.. Linux have solutions for almost any problem!</p>

<p>If you are using Ubuntu or any other distribution base on Ubuntu (like Linux Mint and Elementary OS), you won&rsquo;t feel the difference. Ubuntu apply their own patches to the default font rendering system so their fonts look extremely good. But if you want to improve it further or if you are coming from another Linux distribution, here&rsquo;s a solution&hellip;</p>

<h2>Infinality &hellip;</h2>

<p><a href="http://www.infinality.net/blog/">Infinality</a> is a set of patches made to improve freetype2 font rendering in Linux. It automatically adjust settings like hinting and subpixel rendering to give the best quality fonts for you.</p>

<blockquote><p>The purpose of these patches is to freely provide the nicest font rendering of any operating system. The second goal is to provide customization so that the end user is able to adjust the settings to his or her taste.</p></blockquote>

<h2>How to install Infinality &hellip;</h2>

<h3>On Arch Linux :</h3>

<ul>
<li>Make sure you have <a href="https://wiki.archlinux.org/index.php/Yaourt">Yaourt</a> installed</li>
<li>Next install Infinality with the following commands :</li>
</ul>


<figure class='code'><div class="highlight"><table><tr><td class="gutter"><pre class="line-numbers"><span class='line-number'>1</span>
<span class='line-number'>2</span>
</pre></td><td class='code'><pre><code class=''><span class='line'>sudo yaourt freetype2-git-infinality
</span><span class='line'>sudo yaourt fontconfig-infinality-git</span></code></pre></td></tr></table></div></figure>


<p>**If you have a 64bit system, you also have to install this :</p>

<figure class='code'><div class="highlight"><table><tr><td class="gutter"><pre class="line-numbers"><span class='line-number'>1</span>
</pre></td><td class='code'><pre><code class=''><span class='line'>sudo yaourt lib32-freetype2-git-infinality</span></code></pre></td></tr></table></div></figure>


<ul>
<li>Finally, use this command to choose what style you need (choose from debug, Linux, OSx2, OSx, Win98, WinXP, Win7 and Infinality) :</li>
</ul>


<figure class='code'><div class="highlight"><table><tr><td class="gutter"><pre class="line-numbers"><span class='line-number'>1</span>
</pre></td><td class='code'><pre><code class=''><span class='line'>sudo infctl setstyle</span></code></pre></td></tr></table></div></figure>


<h3>On Ubuntu :</h3>

<ul>
<li>You can install Infinality in Ubuntu with these commands :</li>
</ul>


<figure class='code'><div class="highlight"><table><tr><td class="gutter"><pre class="line-numbers"><span class='line-number'>1</span>
<span class='line-number'>2</span>
<span class='line-number'>3</span>
<span class='line-number'>4</span>
</pre></td><td class='code'><pre><code class=''><span class='line'>sudo add-apt-repository ppa:no1wantdthisname/ppa
</span><span class='line'>sudo apt-get update
</span><span class='line'>sudo apt-get upgrade
</span><span class='line'>sudo apt-get install fontconfig-infinality</span></code></pre></td></tr></table></div></figure>


<ul>
<li>Finally, use this command to select a style :</li>
</ul>


<figure class='code'><div class="highlight"><table><tr><td class="gutter"><pre class="line-numbers"><span class='line-number'>1</span>
</pre></td><td class='code'><pre><code class=''><span class='line'>sudo bash /etc/fonts/infinality/infctl.sh setstyle</span></code></pre></td></tr></table></div></figure>


<h3>On Fedora :</h3>

<ul>
<li>You can find instructions on how to install these patches in Fedora on this <a href="http://www.infinality.net/forum/viewtopic.php?f=2&amp;t=77">page</a></li>
</ul>


<h3>On Debian :</h3>

<ul>
<li>Here are the instructions <a href="http://forums.debian.net/viewtopic.php?f=16&amp;t=88545">for Debian</a></li>
</ul>


<h3>On all systems&hellip;</h3>

<ul>
<li>After you are done installing, log off and login for the changes to take effect.</li>
</ul>


<p>Did it work? If not, please let us know!</p>

<p><em><strong>Image Source :</strong></em> <a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/tarale/2897185492/">Taryn</a></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Tech Hamlet 15 : No WordPress! Faster... Clean.. And Much Better!]]></title>
    <link href="http://techhamlet.com/2013/08/techhamlet-15/"/>
    <updated>2013-08-04T21:40:00+05:30</updated>
    <id>http://techhamlet.com/2013/08/techhamlet-15</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>After a very long time of inactivity, we are coming back again! Everyone&hellip; Say hello to Tech Hamlet 15.0! This not just a simple redesign&hellip; The platform have changed&hellip;  The server have changed&hellip;  The policies have changed&hellip;  The way we work have changed&hellip; The layout have changed
&hellip; What we write have changed&hellip;  The design have changed&hellip;  The core code have changed&hellip;  Everything have changed in Tech Hamlet!</p>

<p><img src="http://techhamlet.com/images/post-images/2013/08/techhamlet-15.jpg" alt="Tech Hamlet 15" /></p>

<h2>Problems with the old site :</h2>

<ul>
<li><p><strong>WordPress</strong> : Yep&hellip;  <a href="http://wordpress.org/">WordPress</a> became a problem to us! Its one of the most popular and the most powerful blogging platforms on earth.  But its getting too heavy.  There are a lot of unwanted features.  We can&rsquo;t  blame WordPress.  Now that platform is used for a lot of applications.  It&rsquo;s not just a blogging platform.  Now it&rsquo;s used for blogging, marketing sites, portfolios, and as a CMS for many different kinds of sites. It&rsquo;s a mess. Unless you do a full optimization of the server,  the theme and the WordPress core itself,  you might have to spend a huge amount of money to find a good host for it. That&rsquo;s the same thing that happened to me. A Web site need to load really fast.  But WordPress have a lot of code to be generated before showing the site to the user. It&rsquo;s a big problem!</p></li>
<li><p><strong>Ads</strong> : The first major problem we had is with Advertisements and Paid links! That&rsquo;s what drive most of the blogging community. People sell links and place ads on their websites without focusing on the contents. I hated this. But I also had to sell links and ads to keep the blog running.  I spent a lot of money for the host because I wanted to make things a lot faster. But recently I did a small survey and found out that a lot of people hate ads.  They draw the attention of the users.  That&rsquo;s what we want.  But that&rsquo;s not what our readers want.  They come here for valuable content.  Not for ads. Selling links is the other problem. Too many links = bad SEO. We even received a penalty from good old Google!</p></li>
<li><p><strong>Guest posts</strong> : You will be amazed to see how many guest posts we receive. It always give me head aches when trying to go through all these emails. Sometimes, Tech Hamlet publish many irrelevant guest posts than relevant articles from us. Most of the guest posts we receive are off topic and doesn&rsquo;t even make sense! With them, we get links. A lot of linking from the guest posts. This is also a major reason that made Google award us a cool penalty!</p></li>
<li><p><strong>Clutter</strong> : The old Tech Hamlet had too much clutter. A lot of sidebar widgets, a lot of bits and pieces in a post page. All of them steal away the reader&rsquo;s attention. That&rsquo;s not good. It started as a simple design but later turned into a cluttered porcupine!</p></li>
<li><p><strong>The design and the layout</strong> : I made that old design and it looked really good to me. But there were some problems. Too much white in the design made it hard for some people to read. The font is not good. Actually every-time I tried to put a completely new design, WordPress stopped me. Its hard to change the WordPress layout. We can do it but it will be reverted back to defaults when we update. That&rsquo;s not good. The other problem with the design is that its old. Many blogs have already upgraded to modern designs!</p></li>
<li><p><strong>Categories</strong> : Most of the categories were added back in 2009. I wanted to add as much categories as I can but later it turned out to be a disaster. If we use a wider category model, then it only keep growing. We had to add more categories and it became a bit out of control! Categories should simply tell the reader what we have. But our categories told them that we are making a fruit salad!</p></li>
<li><p><strong>WordPress plugins and speed</strong> : In order to get the right functionality, I had to add a lot of plugins. Several times I tried to prune the plugins but that list never shrieked. Those plugins and the dynamic nature of WordPress made the blog slow. That will make the readers sad too!</p></li>
<li><p><strong>Hosting</strong> : If I need to pay for WordPress hosting, then I need a lot of ads and get my hands dirty. The site need a very powerful server so I had to spend a lot for a good VPS.</p></li>
</ul>


<h2>Our solutions :</h2>

<h3>No more WordPress ! Hello Octopress !</h3>

<p><img src="http://techhamlet.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/06/octopress-550x385.jpg" alt="Octopress" /></p>

<p>WordPress is dead. We have just moved away from that platform to Octopress. Its all about static blogging. The <a href="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</a> framework is built on Jekyll and Ruby. The source code for the website resides in your machine and in a remote git repository (if you need backups). There&rsquo;s a default minimal and responsive design added by Octopress. But you are free to change it. I have done a lot of customization to the default Octopress layout. You can&rsquo;t say its a Octopress site by just looking at it! I have added the following features to make it more powerful :</p>

<ul>
<li>Featured images for posts. Every post will have a <code>fimage</code> tag. The site will pull the image path from this tag and use it to display a post image in the index and in the sidebar recent posts.</li>
<li>Featured posts. If the <code>featured</code> tag is set to true in a post, the blog index will style that post differently. (For example, add a bigger image to it)</li>
<li>Auto excerpts. Octopress have excerpts. The only thing is you have to add the <code>&lt;!--more--&gt;</code> tag manually. I imported nearly 1,500 posts from my old WordPress setup. I can&rsquo;t go through all these posts and add the more tag manually! So, I used the <code>truncatewords</code> method in Liquid Templates like this :</li>
</ul>


<figure class='code'><div class="highlight"><table><tr><td class="gutter"><pre class="line-numbers"><span class='line-number'>1</span>
</pre></td><td class='code'><pre><code class=''><span class='line'>post.content | strip_html | truncatewords: 30</span></code></pre></td></tr></table></div></figure>


<ul>
<li>One of the best things about Octopress is that you can get free hosting on Github. But there&rsquo;s a problem&hellip; If you upload the source to Github (Free account), anyone can get your posts easily (Thats what I think. Im not sure). You can push the source to a different place like Bitbucket. But it won&rsquo;t make the source open. So, I pushed the posts, pages and their images to my private repository in Bitbucket and left the source in Github. This bring another problem. You need to push the source, pages, posts and images separately to their own origins which can become a big headache. But, I created two scripts to <strong>commit</strong> and <strong>push</strong>. To take care of all the repositories from one script. I will write about it in <a href="http://techhamlet.com/">Tech Hamlet</a> in the near future. (They are not included in the source).</li>
<li>Auto generated open graph meta tags for each and every page</li>
<li>And there are some more tiny things I added&hellip;</li>
</ul>


<p>If you want to use these features on your own site, you can check the <a href="https://github.com/TechHamlet/TechHamlet.github.io">source code of Tech Hamlet</a>. Now its open sourced!</p>

<p>After you setup the layouts, you are ready to go. Then you write the posts. After that, with two commands, Octopress will generate a static HTML version of your site and automatically push it to the server. You are done! In the future, I will write some posts about Octopress so you also can follow. Because its static HTML, Tech Hamlet is now a lot faster than before. The web server doesn&rsquo;t have to generate any heavy php before sending it to you. Its already built.</p>

<h3>Almost NO ADS!</h3>

<p>Tech Hamlet 15.0 doesn&rsquo;t have any adsense ads&hellip; No links will be sold from both the blogroll and from posts. We will only have two 125x125 ads in the sidebar. Only two small ads for the whole site. It will be enough to keep the ship afloat. It will also please our readers. No ads mean less clutter. Now things are more organized and clean. When designing the previous versions of Tech Hamlet, first it looked like a very nice design. But after I inserted the ads to the template I got sad :( . They made everything look ugly. There&rsquo;s no way I can tell what ad Google will place on my site. So it posed a major problem. Now we don&rsquo;t have them! Cool isn&rsquo;t it?</p>

<h3>No more irrelevant guest posts</h3>

<p>The <a href="http://techhamlet.com/contact/">guest posts rules</a> are tightened. If you are here just to get a link to your product or to get a link for your client, no matter how much money you are willing to pay, we won&rsquo;t accept your gust post. If you are willing to write a quality article that is related to our site, we will let you write. We will also let you link to your own blog. Not to a product. People who link to products mostly write rubbish!</p>

<h3>No more clutter!</h3>

<p>Many things have been removed from the site. There&rsquo;s nothing much in the sidebar. Its cleaned. The post pages are also clean. No big author bios and multiple social share buttons. You can find three popular share buttons at the bottom. That&rsquo;s all!</p>

<h3>A more cleaner and a unique design&hellip;</h3>

<p>Unlike WordPress, the Octopress layout can be easily changed. I did a lot of customization to the default layout and then added my own theme. I tried to make something unique. For example, the way I added the category links in the header is a bit crazy. But I think it will work.</p>

<h3>Less categories&hellip;</h3>

<p>As I mentioned before, adding more categories made the site look like a fruit salad. But now I have reduced it to 5. 5 main categories to group every thing. Now our goal is clear. Its not a fruit salad any more!</p>

<h3>Hosting</h3>

<p>Since I use Octopress and generate a static HTML site, I can get free hosting on <a href="https://github.com">Github</a>! Some people doesn&rsquo;t go for free hosting because most of those hosting providers cannot be trusted and some even put ads on our sites. But Github is the world&rsquo;s number one source code host! Millions of developers use it every day. So, there&rsquo;s no question about their quality. Both the source code and the website can be hosted in Github.</p>

<h3>There are more&hellip;</h3>

<p>Apart from that, there are more changes to our site. For example, we will now reduce the amount of news posts we add. There are a lot of websites out there which does the job better than us. So, if there&rsquo;s some big news topic, then I&rsquo;ll write about it. Mostly, we will focus on tutorials and reviews.</p>

<p>Earlier, our markup didn&rsquo;t pass W3 validations. Even-though I managed to make the site&rsquo;s design W3 valid, after adding WordPress plugins, the validations failed. But now, the site is W3 valid!</p>

<p>Today we placed a big milestone for our blog. Many things have changed and will be changed in the future. I didn&rsquo;t got time and interest to update the blog in the past few weeks. I&rsquo;m turning into a developer. Octopress is extremely developer friendly. It use the tools we use every day like Git and Markdown. I like it! First I converted my other site <a href="http://youarecurio.us/">YouAreCurio.us</a> into Octopress and immediately felt its power.</p>

<p>I think Tech Hamlet will have a very bight future with these new changes. In a way, we have joined the open source developer community! Cool! So, what do you think about our new changes? Please let us know as comments below&hellip;</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Bitdefender 2014 is Released! Its Faster, Lighter and More Secure!]]></title>
    <link href="http://techhamlet.com/2013/06/bitdefender-2014-released/"/>
    <updated>2013-06-26T21:22:14+05:30</updated>
    <id>http://techhamlet.com/2013/06/bitdefender-2014-released</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="http://techhamlet.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/06/bitdefender2014-550x385.jpg" alt="Bitdefender 2014" /> Bitdefender 2014</p>

<p>Folks at Bitdefender have just released a major upgrade to their security suits! The new Bitdefender 2014 is now available for everyone! Bitdefender started to test this new version a bit earlier than in the previous years. They released the first <a href="http://techhamlet.com/2013/03/bitdefender-2014-beta/">public beta</a> version on March. After testing for about 4 months, they have just released the new security suit today.</p>

<h3>Bitdefender 2014&hellip;</h3>

<p><a href="http://www.bitdefender.com/solutions/internet-security.html">Bitdefender 2014</a> &rsquo;s main point is speed. According to Bitdefender, their new photon technology will make things a lot lighter. That means, the anti virus will be a lot faster! Not only the anti virus, even the whole system will be faster. Normally, an anti virus can significantly slow down a computer. Some people don&rsquo;t even use anti virus apps for this reason. But with this new technology, Bitdefender 2014 might change the way how people think about security suits.</p>

<p>Apart from the speed, there are a lot of security enhancements, enhancements to<a href="http://techhamlet.com/2013/06/bitdefender-safepay/"> safepay</a>, cloud anti spam and some new features. The developers have also changed the look and feel of the app. Now its even more smoother. Will glide through your system smoothly protecting every corner of it!</p>

<p>Currently, according to independent lab tests, Bitdefender is the number one security suit on the planet. If you read of blog earlier, you should know this. That&rsquo;s why we always follow their products. Recently, they have also gained the crown in Android security which was earlier held by Trust Go. Now, if you already have Bitdefender, you can install this new version free of charge. If you want to buy it, please wait. We might hold a free giveaway of Bitdefender 2014 ! Want to grab a free key to this awesome security suit? Just be patient and wait&hellip; Also if you need to learn more on this new Bitdefender, wait for my full review.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[A better understanding of Software as a Service]]></title>
    <link href="http://techhamlet.com/2013/06/a-better-understanding-of-software-as-a-service/"/>
    <updated>2013-06-26T10:23:50+05:30</updated>
    <id>http://techhamlet.com/2013/06/a-better-understanding-of-software-as-a-service</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>For most of us, it&rsquo;s easy to think of software as a product. After all, you can purchase it in a shop and, for the most part, it works in a similar fashion.</p>

<p>The truth is, however, that we do not own the software we use. Anything you purchase is not yours. Instead you only own a licence; this is a common business model known as “Software as a Service” or SaaS for short.</p>

<p>To help understand this, here&rsquo;s a quick look at how this approach actually works and why, in cases where the software is rather important to you or your work, you may want to look into <a href="http://www.nccgroup.com/en/our-services/software-escrow-verification">software escrow</a> to further protect yourself.</p>

<p><img src="http://techhamlet.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/07/app_saas_img2.jpg" alt="Software as a Service" /> Software as a Service</p>

<h3>The License</h3>

<p>At its simplest, software is typically a licence, not a product. This is why you have to agree and enter into an end user agreement for most software products as this enters you into a SaaS agreement with the software provider.</p>

<p>The drawback to this is that you don&rsquo;t have access to the software&rsquo;s inner workings or source code. The advantage, however, is that it&rsquo;s not up to you to maintain the software. As your only leasing it, it’s up to the provider to offer a working product throughout this time. Should that fail to happen, disputes can happen and this is where escrow can become important.</p>

<h3>Verifying perspective</h3>

<p>In any dispute, it&rsquo;s easy to get drawn out into a longer disagreement. When you need software fast, such as when you rely or depend upon it for work, this isn&rsquo;t the best option. A lot of disagreements come around due to both sides being unable to agree on a solution. Instead, you should look to <a href="http://www.nccgroup.com/en/our-services/software-escrow-verification">escrow</a> to provide a neutral perspective from a legal stand point.</p>

<p>Escrow companies can verify software and make the right actions in accordance with the law. This should keep both sides happy but the simple act of putting the software in escrow ensures that the provider is serious about keeping their product in working order.</p>

<p>In many cases, it can be a simple sign of trust or added security. Developers design their software, as a product, to work, but having the added security layer of escrow support means both sides just want a working product. Should it come to it, the use of escrow will ensure, in cases where the agreement has been broken, you&rsquo;re given what you&rsquo;re legally entitled to.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Mac OS X vs Linux : What is The Best Windows Alternative? Mac or Linux]]></title>
    <link href="http://techhamlet.com/2013/06/mac-os-x-vs-linux/"/>
    <updated>2013-06-22T19:23:20+05:30</updated>
    <id>http://techhamlet.com/2013/06/mac-os-x-vs-linux</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="http://techhamlet.com/wp-content/uploads/2012/12/update_for_your_computer.jpg" alt="Mac OS X vs Linux" /> Mac OS X vs Linux <em>Image source : <a href="http://www.stickycomics.com/computer-update/">Sticky Comics</a></em></p>

<p>Mac OS X vs Linux, this is not an easy debate. Most of us start with Windows because it&rsquo;s the most commonly used OS. But that doesn&rsquo;t mean its the best. Many migrate to other alternatives according to their needs. But the recent the Windows 8 release made some users to <a href="http://techhamlet.com/2013/06/windows-8-is-not-user-friendly/">leave Windows</a>. For some its really good but for some it&rsquo;s not. Windows now have a problem. So, if you ever decide to ditch Windows, what will you pick? Mac or Linux?</p>

<h3>Why Windows is more popular?</h3>

<p>The biggest reason for Windows&rsquo;s popularity is the support from manufacturers! Most of the PCs and Notebooks come with Windows pre-installed! Only an experienced user who have already used a different OS will try to change it. People like Dell and HP have already started to ship Linux pre-installed machines. But still it&rsquo;s not enough to beat Windows. Mac also have their own machines. So, they both stay ahead of Linux. Not good for Mac OS X vs Linux battle.</p>

<h3>Mac and Linux have some similarities&hellip;</h3>

<p>Mac OS X is based on Unix. They take Unix and add their own GUI to it. GNU/Linux is like Unix but it&rsquo;s not Unix. Richard Stalleman wanted to build a free, open sourced and a better system than Unix. So, he built his own system from scratch by looking at Unix. He called it GNU. GNU means, <strong>G</strong>nu <strong>I</strong>s <strong>N</strong>ot <strong>U</strong>nix! After adding the Linux kernel to it, we dropped the word GNU and used Linux. But the OS is GNU.</p>

<h3>They have a lot of differences! So, lets start the debate, Mac OS X vs Linux :</h3>

<h4>Firest of all, Linux is free and open source and Mac OS X is expensive!</h4>

<p>The first reason you might pick Mac over Linux (in the battle of Mac OSX vs Linux) is the price. Mac is expensive. More expensive than Windows. There are many free apps for Windows which might be enough for an average user. But Mac apps are also expensive. You have to pay for most of the stuff!</p>

<p>Mac is completely closed sourced. They take full revenge from those who copy at least a single word from their system. They take patents for every thing including every curve and line in their designs. If anyone copy them, they will go directly to the court.</p>

<p>Linux is completely free. If some one ask to pay you to get a Linux distribution, you can sue him. According to their license, you can&rsquo;t sell it and make profits. You can get money for the service you provide, but can&rsquo;t make a profit.</p>

<p>The Linux code is completely open sourced. You can get it and customize it in any way you want, add your name to it and distribute it to the world.</p>

<h4>Mac OS X won&rsquo;t let you customize their OS&hellip; You can customize every corner of Linux!</h4>

<p>In OS X, you can&rsquo;t customize much. You have to do things in their way. Apple will decide how your desktop will look like and how you will work with it. You must obey them. There&rsquo;s no other choice! If you are a newbie who don&rsquo;t do much with the computer, then OS X will be ok for you!</p>

<p>Linux is open sourced. You can customize every single bit of the OS if you know how to do it. Unlike other operating systems, Linux is built to support third party themes. There are high quality themes that you can use. No hacking needed. It&rsquo;s originally supported. You will also get a lot of options. A lot of different desktop environments, Gnome, XFC, Cinnamon, Unity, KDE, etc&hellip; A lot of different themes&hellip; A lot of different gadgets like docks, widgets, desk lets, etc</p>

<h4>Mac OS X vs Linux Performance&hellip;</h4>

<p>A recent study have revealed that Ubuntu in a Mac can outperform OS X! Beating OS X in its own grounds! The clear winner is Linux&hellip;</p>

<h4>Ease of use, ease of learning and ease of migrating from Windows&hellip;</h4>

<p>I have tried Mac&hellip; If you are moving from Windows to OS X, you might get into trouble. Some shortcuts might not work, it will scroll in the opposite direction, more weird things will happen&hellip; Linux is also different. It have a lot of differences. But its easy to move from Windows. and its easy to learn.<a href="http://www.youtube.com/user/OsFirstTimer?feature=watch"> OsFirstTimer</a> have released several videos on this issues. In these videos, a completely new user will face different operating systems and review them. From the systems she used, she picked Linux as the best :</p>

<h4>Support&hellip;</h4>

<p>When we take support, it&rsquo;s a tie. Apple provide a really good support for their products. Linux have a really good support from thousands of people in the community. So, both have good support.</p>

<h4>Security&hellip;</h4>

<p>Earlier Apple said OS X is completely impenetrable. But recently, a mass malware attack took down thousands of Mac users. It&rsquo;s not completely secure. Same goes to Linux. No mass malware attack took down Linux but still it&rsquo;s not completely secure. It&rsquo;s a tie. But both are better than Windows.</p>

<h4>Mac is boring&hellip; No innovation&hellip;</h4>

<p>People say Apple is innovative. Yes they are innovative. They release completely new awesome products. But after the initial release of the product, no major updates. No major features&hellip; No much changes&hellip; The same boring old thing will get minor updates and bug fixes for the rest of its life. Its old stuff. Boring&hellip;</p>

<p>Linux and Windows do complete re-designs occasionally. Linux know how to do their redesigns without killing the user. It have innovation! Mac OS X vs Linux, who is the best?</p>

<h3>What is the most widely used OS?</h3>

<p>You might say its Windows but it&rsquo;s not. The most widely used OS is Linux! The mobile world is dominated by Android and Android is a Linux distribution. Almost 90% of web servers run Linux. Many embedded systems have Linux, Super computers run on Linux. Linux is the king&hellip;</p>

<h3>Mac OS X vs Linux&hellip; What is the best?</h3>

<p>Clearly, Linux is the better option. Mac users will fire at me but this is the truth. Many people buy Apple products to show that they are rich. Trust me, that&rsquo;s the truth. If not, why spend a lot of money just to buy a boring old product? Their support is extremely good. Is it worth it? Once I tried to buy a new notebook and considered Mac. I was unable to find a powerful enough Mac to replace my existing old notebook! A Mac can&rsquo;t replace its power. You might say you&rsquo;re going for the OS X. But isn&rsquo;t Linux better than OS X? If you want the OS X look, it won&rsquo;t take 30 minutes to transform your Linux desktop into a Mac. But you can never transform Mac into a Linux! That&rsquo;s the difference! Mac users are trapped inside Apple&rsquo;s prison while Linux people are free to do anything! The clear winner in the battle of Mac OS X vs Linux is Linux!</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Firefox Beats Chrome In Many Ways]]></title>
    <link href="http://techhamlet.com/2013/06/firefox-beats-chrome/"/>
    <updated>2013-06-20T19:34:26+05:30</updated>
    <id>http://techhamlet.com/2013/06/firefox-beats-chrome</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="http://techhamlet.com/wp-content/uploads/2012/05/browser-war-550x385.jpg" alt="Firefox vs Chrome" /> <em>Image Source : <a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/50186930@N00/5948520195/">JUDEE</a></em></p>

<p>Yesterday I had a good chuckle at my friends words &lsquo;Chrome never ceases to amaze me&rsquo; Personally, I find lots of problems with Google&rsquo;s so called wonder browser Chrome and although I do use it sometimes to try new add-ons that sound interesting, I prefer to stick with Firefox.</p>

<p>Here&rsquo;s what annoys me most about Chrome: firstly, it uses tons of memory; a lot more, in fact, than Firefox, which people accuse of being slower. Just bring up your Task Manager when you&rsquo;re running Chrome to see how many different processes it has open &ndash; one for each tab &ndash; and how much memory it&rsquo;s using. I guarantee you&rsquo;ll be surprised.</p>

<p>Secondly, its always crashing and showing that stupid &lsquo;He&rsquo;s dead Jim&rsquo; message as if the inconvenience were supposed to be funny. And you can bet that when your PC hangs on shutdown because a program needs to be closed the culprit is Chrome. LOL.</p>

<p>I also dislike the often scary list of permissions, you need to agree to when installing certain extensions, giving them access to your data on all websites, as well as your tabs, bookmarks and browsing activity. Given Google&rsquo;s notoriety for storing personal info, these permissions make me paranoid, no matter how harmless they may be. Firefox add-ons don&rsquo;t make these demands so why would Chrome get away with it?</p>

<h3>Firefox vs Chrome, who is the winner?</h3>

<p>If you ask me, Chrome is very overrated, especially compared to more innovative browsers such as Opera, Maxthon and yes Firefox. I also prefer Mozilla&rsquo;s non-profit ethos to Google&rsquo;s sneaky tax-avoiding tricks, and find bookmarks much easier to manage in Firefox. My friend is entitled to his views, bit look closer at Chrome and you&rsquo;ll see the cracks.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Just Moved You Are Curious from Wordpress to Octopress!]]></title>
    <link href="http://techhamlet.com/2013/06/wordpress-to-octopress/"/>
    <updated>2013-06-18T10:53:47+05:30</updated>
    <id>http://techhamlet.com/2013/06/wordpress-to-octopress</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="http://techhamlet.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/06/octopress-550x385.jpg" alt="Octopress" /> Octopress</p>

<p>I always felt Wordpress is too much for me. I wanted something simple, something more customizable and something really fast! So, why not go with Octopress? It&rsquo;s a blogging platform that runs on your own machine. It generate static HTML files and upload them to the server. No dynamic content. That means the website is extremely fast! You have a local copy and Git is already used by the framework which you can use to send backups to remote servers like Github and Bitbucket. Its fast, reliable and extremely customizable!</p>

<p>Octopress is a platform built on Jekyll which use Ruby to generate static HTML blogs. You write your posts in Markdown and place them in a separate folder. When generating the website, Octopress will use these markdown files and the layouts you defined to generate your website. Its a bit geeky but you can learn it. Octopress have a very good documentation which will guide you through all the steps. After generating, you just have to push it to the web server. If you need to move to a new server, you don&rsquo;t have to run complex scripts and setup databases. Just push to the new address and the website will work.</p>

<p>You might think that we need dynamic stuff for comments. Actually, I already use Disqus. Octopress have built in Disqus integration which can be used for comments. I just moved my site without loosing any of the existing comments!</p>

<p>For hosting, you can use any simple web server. Any server can serve simple static HTML files. You also don&rsquo;t need a big server because there are no server-side scripting used in Octopress. You can even host the site in GitHub for free! I used that option. The website&rsquo;s code is now open sourced!</p>

<h3>Read more about Octopress &hellip;</h3>

<p>What do you think? Octopress have all the thing I need. No extra stuff to slow down the site. You can read more about Octopress and even enjoy my new site if you go there now : <a href="http://youarecurio.us/2013/06/wordpress-to-octopress/">Moved From Wordpress to Octopress! Simple, Faster and More Reliable!</a></p>

<p>For Tech Hamlet, I have bigger plans! Read that post and see what im planning for Tech Hamlet!</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Bitdefender Safepay : A More Secure Browser for Your Critical Work!]]></title>
    <link href="http://techhamlet.com/2013/06/bitdefender-safepay/"/>
    <updated>2013-06-17T20:41:28+05:30</updated>
    <id>http://techhamlet.com/2013/06/bitdefender-safepay</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="http://techhamlet.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/06/safepay-550x412.jpg" alt="Bitdefender Safepay" /> Bitdefender Safepay</p>

<p>If you are banking online, buying things from an online store or doing other critical stuff like this, many people will try their best to get their hand on your details. Your credit card information, the passwords, user names, emails, these stuff can ruin your life if they go to the wrong hands. But, the problem is, the Internet is full of these hands trying to grab your data. Is there a way to get rid of them? You can&rsquo;t get rid of every threat, but Bitdefender Safepay will help you stay away from most of them!</p>

<p>Bitdefender is the number one security suit in the industry and they have kept that place for years. Recently, they introduced a cool new feature in their security suit named Bitdefender Safepay. It is a browser. But not an ordinary one. Its more secure. A normal browser doesn&rsquo;t enforce all the security features because it will slow down the normal browsing. But Bitdefender Safepay have them enabled.</p>

<p>First of all, it will scan your machine for threats and warn you if there&rsquo;s something wrong. If there&rsquo;s something that can tap your data and ruin your life. Then, when you deal with online banks, stores and other critical sites, it will secure your whole connection, and the browser environment you are working. It will isolate the browser from the rest of the system and make sure no one can tap into it. It also have a virtual keyboard which can be used to prevent keyloggers from logging your data and sending them to the hackers! Bitdefender Safepay can also protect you from unsecured Wi-Fi connections by securing the whole connection. Normally, if you use an unsecured public hot spot, there are a lot of chances that your data might get hacked. But <a href="http://www.bitdefender.com/media/html/beta-safepay/index.html">Bitdefender Safepay</a> can rescue you.</p>

<p>Bitdefender offered all these cool features as an add-on in their security suit. So, you need to install Bitdefender in order to get this functionality. But Bitdefender doesn&rsquo;t want to keep it only for their own customers. They are getting ready to release it to every one! Now even if you don&rsquo;t have Bitdefender, you can install Bitdefender Safepay Beta and use the highly secured browser for your critical work!</p>

<p>The product is still in beta stage and might have some bugs. But still its worth trying out because the <a href="http://youarecurio.us/2013/05/internet-is-evil/">internet is getting dangerous</a> everyday! Bitdefender have also organized a small contest where they will give fabulous prizes to those who help them test their beta product! Download and try Bitdefender Safepay now!</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Does the iPhone 6 Represent the Future?]]></title>
    <link href="http://techhamlet.com/2013/06/iphone-6-represent-the-future/"/>
    <updated>2013-06-17T20:16:38+05:30</updated>
    <id>http://techhamlet.com/2013/06/iphone-6-represent-the-future</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Although there is still no official word from Apple about the latest iPhone incarnation, several creative individuals continue to come up with some unique design and concept ideas to get the public’s imagination racing.</p>

<p>In the past we have seen built-in projectors, virtual laser keyboards and even 3D cameras. However, this latest concept combines technology that is currently available with innovations that every Smartphone manufacturer strives for.</p>

<p><img src="http://techhamlet.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/06/iphone6-550x385.jpg" alt="iPhone 6" /> <em>Image Source : <a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/thronx/8008932080/">thronx</a></em></p>

<h3>Water-resistant and dustproof</h3>

<p>Even though the iPhone 5 has shown itself to be fairly resistant to water in recent consumer tests, this concept takes inspiration from other Smartphones available on the market.</p>

<p>Sony&#8217;s Experia Z, released in February 2013, has Ingress Protection Ratings of IP55 and IP57, making it dustproof and water-resistant. Able to deal with one metre of water for up to thirty minutes, the Experia Z is one of the world&rsquo;s toughest Smartphones.</p>

<p>Last year, speculation suggested that Apple was working on a water-resistant coating for its products, meaning such protection from the elements would be a distinct possibility. However, with full control over its component supply chain, Apple might be content with the money it makes from repairs.</p>

<h3>Wireless charging</h3>

<p>In what is considered by several commentators to be the holy grail of technological progress, this iPhone 6 concept also manages to achieve wireless charging.</p>

<p>Even with some great <a href="http://www.buymobilephones.net/mobile-phones/apple">Apple iPhone deals</a> available, messy cables and tangled wires have been one of the most frustrating aspects about owning a Smartphone. Manufacturers including Nokia, LG and HTC have all recently championed the technology, but there has yet to be any solid inductive charging evidence from Apple.</p>

<p>However, when you consider that Samsung&rsquo;s Galaxy S4, the iPhone&rsquo;s main smartphone rival, now supports wireless charging, it certainly makes sense for Apple to pursue the technology.</p>

<h3>Other notable features</h3>

<p>Additional innovations include touch-sensitive casing and LED notifications, taking influence from some recent Apple patents.</p>

<p>Although LED notifications on either side of the casing is a novel idea, current iPhone users already have this option via the camera&rsquo;s flashlight. Up until now, Apple has favoured physical buttons. However, there are various aesthetic and design advantages to touch-sensitive controls.</p>

<p>It remains to be seen whether the iPhone 6 will include these advances. However, with rival Smartphones already featuring such additions, Apple should certainly take note.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Firefox OS to Launch on Foxconn Tablets]]></title>
    <link href="http://techhamlet.com/2013/06/firefox-os-launch-on-foxconn/"/>
    <updated>2013-06-15T20:32:54+05:30</updated>
    <id>http://techhamlet.com/2013/06/firefox-os-launch-on-foxconn</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://techhamlet.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/06/Firefox-OS_tablet_610x416.jpg"><img src="http://techhamlet.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/06/Firefox-OS_tablet_610x416-300x204.jpg" alt="Firefox OS to launch on Foxconn tablets" /></a> Firefox OS to launch on Foxconn tablets</p>

<p>Firefox is ready to launch their OS soon this summer.
<strong>
</strong></p>

<h3><strong>What Happened?</strong></h3>

<p>Browser developer Mozilla and hardware manufacturer Foxconn signed a deal to create devices running open-source mobile OS. Mozilla had already signed up smartphone makers to use its OS on their handsets. Foxconn is a Chinese manufacturer that produces hardware for a host of big tech companies, including Apple.</p>

<p><strong>
</strong></p>

<h3><strong>How will it affect you? The Firefox OS</strong></h3>

<p>This is a big win if you&rsquo;re a Firefox fan and could help propel the new operating system onto other devices. This OS focuses on HTML rather than apps, which means for example you can use the Facebook mobile site rather than download an app. It also has strong privacy controls. The Firefox OS tablets will offer a competitive alternative to Google and Apple devices.</p>

<p><strong>
</strong></p>

<h3><strong>What does Techhamlet think about Firefox OS?</strong></h3>

<p>This is Foxconns first big move into making its own branded hardware and that&rsquo;s big news for Firefox. We think it will give Mozilla a head start in the Chinese market and could lead to other hardware makers adopting the software.</p>

<blockquote><p>If Foxconn&rsquo;s tablets are a success then Firefox OS will be too</p></blockquote>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[BBM Coming To Android]]></title>
    <link href="http://techhamlet.com/2013/06/bbm-coming-to-android/"/>
    <updated>2013-06-15T20:31:42+05:30</updated>
    <id>http://techhamlet.com/2013/06/bbm-coming-to-android</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://techhamlet.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/06/bbm.jpg"><img src="http://techhamlet.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/06/bbm-300x176.jpg" alt="Blackberry Messenger BBM coming to Android this summer" /></a> Blackberry Messenger BBM coming to Android this summer</p>

<blockquote><p>The once venerable messaging service BBM makes its belated move to Android this summer.</p></blockquote>

<p>Blackberry has announced that its flagship BBM will be coming to Android this summer. It will be available as a free download from the Play Store, and will compete with the likes of Google&rsquo;s new Hangouts app, Facebook Home and WhatsApp in the battle to dominate the mobile messaging space.</p>

<blockquote><p>The move to make BBM cross platform was first mooted two years ago</p>

<p>It will also be available for iOS</p></blockquote>

<p>Blackberry was the market leader in messaging and ranked among the worlds biggest smartphone manufacturers. Today the company&rsquo;s share stands at less than 3% and falling. The same figures put Android&rsquo;s share at a whopping 75%.</p>

<p>Messaging is increasingly becoming one of the key battlegrounds in the mobile, and is seen as one of the best ways to lock users into a particular platform. Meanwhile &lsquo;over the top&rsquo; messaging apps are plentiful. It&rsquo;s into this crowded market that BBM is making its move. The brand may be diminished and the decision may appear to be a last resort for Blackberry, but the app and service are still more than competitive and fondly remembered by many of its past users. That should at least guarantee a certain level of interest in the app when it arrives this summer.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[How To Fix Ugly Ubuntu Login Resolution Issues in Multi-Monitor Setups]]></title>
    <link href="http://techhamlet.com/2013/06/how-to-fix-ugly-ubuntu-login/"/>
    <updated>2013-06-13T20:08:44+05:30</updated>
    <id>http://techhamlet.com/2013/06/how-to-fix-ugly-ubuntu-login</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>If you install Ubuntu in a multi-monitor environment, earlier, you had to face a lot of issues. But now Ubuntu have fixed most of those issues. But one major issues still persists! If you try to login to an Ubuntu machine which have multiple monitors, the Uubntu Greeter (Login Screen) will have a smaller resolution that doesn&rsquo;t fit the monitor. Sometimes it will be stretched or crushed. In simple terms, it will look a lot ugly! Is there a fix for this? Yes!</p>

<p><a href="http://techhamlet.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/06/ubuntu-login-greeter-multi-monitor.jpg"><img src="http://techhamlet.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/06/ubuntu-login-greeter-multi-monitor-550x180.jpg" alt="Fixed Ubuntu Login in a Multi-Monitor Setup" /></a> Fixed Ubuntu Login in a Multi-Monitor Setup</p>

<p>Currently I have a 19 inch and a 23 inch monitor. If I install Ubuntu in my machine, both the monitors will get stretched in the login screen. They won&rsquo;t get the correct resolutions and will look like hell. This bug haunts many people. Many dual monitor setups won&rsquo;t get correct resolutions in the login screen. Actually, it won&rsquo;t give you the correct resolution even in the desktop. But we can fix it simply by changing display settings. But&hellip;</p>

<h3>How to fix the Ubuntu login screen resolution?</h3>

<ul>
<li>First, open the terminal and run Xrandr and get the ids of the connected monitors :</li>
</ul>


<figure class='code'><div class="highlight"><table><tr><td class="gutter"><pre class="line-numbers"><span class='line-number'>1</span>
</pre></td><td class='code'><pre><code class=''><span class='line'>xrandr</span></code></pre></td></tr></table></div></figure>


<ul>
<li> You will get an output like this :</li>
</ul>


<figure class='code'><div class="highlight"><table><tr><td class="gutter"><pre class="line-numbers"><span class='line-number'>1</span>
<span class='line-number'>2</span>
<span class='line-number'>3</span>
<span class='line-number'>4</span>
<span class='line-number'>5</span>
<span class='line-number'>6</span>
<span class='line-number'>7</span>
<span class='line-number'>8</span>
<span class='line-number'>9</span>
<span class='line-number'>10</span>
<span class='line-number'>11</span>
<span class='line-number'>12</span>
<span class='line-number'>13</span>
<span class='line-number'>14</span>
<span class='line-number'>15</span>
<span class='line-number'>16</span>
<span class='line-number'>17</span>
<span class='line-number'>18</span>
<span class='line-number'>19</span>
<span class='line-number'>20</span>
<span class='line-number'>21</span>
<span class='line-number'>22</span>
<span class='line-number'>23</span>
<span class='line-number'>24</span>
<span class='line-number'>25</span>
<span class='line-number'>26</span>
<span class='line-number'>27</span>
<span class='line-number'>28</span>
</pre></td><td class='code'><pre><code class=''><span class='line'>pubudu@pc1:~$ xrandr
</span><span class='line'>Screen 0: minimum 320 x 200, current 3286 x 1080, maximum 32767 x 32767
</span><span class='line'>VGA1 connected 1366x768+1920+0 (normal left inverted right x axis y axis) 410mm x 230mm
</span><span class='line'>   1366x768       59.8*+
</span><span class='line'>   1024x768       75.1     70.1     60.0  
</span><span class='line'>   832x624        74.6  
</span><span class='line'>   800x600        72.2     75.0     60.3     56.2  
</span><span class='line'>   640x480        72.8     75.0     66.7     60.0  
</span><span class='line'>   720x400        70.1  
</span><span class='line'>HDMI1 connected 1920x1080+0+0 (normal left inverted right x axis y axis) 510mm x 287mm
</span><span class='line'>   1920x1080      60.0*+   50.0  
</span><span class='line'>   1680x1050      59.9  
</span><span class='line'>   1600x900       60.0  
</span><span class='line'>   1280x1024      75.0     60.0  
</span><span class='line'>   1440x900       59.9  
</span><span class='line'>   1280x800       59.9  
</span><span class='line'>   1152x864       75.0  
</span><span class='line'>   1280x720       50.0     60.0  
</span><span class='line'>   1024x768       75.1     70.1     60.0  
</span><span class='line'>   832x624        74.6  
</span><span class='line'>   800x600        72.2     75.0     60.3     56.2  
</span><span class='line'>   720x576        50.0  
</span><span class='line'>   720x480        59.9  
</span><span class='line'>   640x480        72.8     75.0     66.7     60.0  
</span><span class='line'>   720x400        70.1  
</span><span class='line'>HDMI2 disconnected (normal left inverted right x axis y axis)
</span><span class='line'>DP1 disconnected (normal left inverted right x axis y axis)
</span><span class='line'>DP2 disconnected (normal left inverted right x axis y axis)</span></code></pre></td></tr></table></div></figure>


<ul>
<li><p>Check the marked lines in the above output (line number 3 and 10). At the start of those lines, you can find the ID of the attached monitors. (In front of attached monitors you will see &ldquo;connected&rdquo;). For me, the IDs of my two monitors are VGA1 and HDMI1. Note them down and also note down the current resolution (in front of the ID and the word &ldquo;connected&rdquo;)</p></li>
<li><p>Next, you have to create a script. Open the terminal and enter  the following command to create the script file :</p></li>
</ul>


<figure class='code'><div class="highlight"><table><tr><td class="gutter"><pre class="line-numbers"><span class='line-number'>1</span>
</pre></td><td class='code'><pre><code class=''><span class='line'>sudo gedit /usr/share/lightdmxrandr.sh</span></code></pre></td></tr></table></div></figure>


<ul>
<li> Then paste the following code in the file :</li>
</ul>


<figure class='code'><div class="highlight"><table><tr><td class="gutter"><pre class="line-numbers"><span class='line-number'>1</span>
<span class='line-number'>2</span>
</pre></td><td class='code'><pre><code class=''><span class='line'>#!/bin/sh
</span><span class='line'>xrandr --output HDMI1 --primary --mode 1920x1080 --output VGA1 --mode 1366x768 --right-of HDMI1</span></code></pre></td></tr></table></div></figure>


<ul>
<li><p>Replace &ldquo;HDMI1&rdquo; and &ldquo;VGA1&rdquo; with the IDs of your own monitor IDs. Also replace the resolution with your own values. If  you have more monitors, add another part to the end of the second line like &ldquo;&mdash;output VGA2 &mdash;mode 1366x768 &mdash;right-of VGA1&rdquo;. Change the VGA1, VGA2 and the resolutions accordingly.</p></li>
<li><p>Now, make the file executable with the following command :</p></li>
</ul>


<figure class='code'><div class="highlight"><table><tr><td class="gutter"><pre class="line-numbers"><span class='line-number'>1</span>
</pre></td><td class='code'><pre><code class=''><span class='line'>sudo chmod a+rx /usr/share/lightdmxrandr.sh</span></code></pre></td></tr></table></div></figure>


<ul>
<li> After that, open the lightdm.conf :</li>
</ul>


<figure class='code'><div class="highlight"><table><tr><td class="gutter"><pre class="line-numbers"><span class='line-number'>1</span>
</pre></td><td class='code'><pre><code class=''><span class='line'>sudo gedit /etc/lightdm/lightdm.conf</span></code></pre></td></tr></table></div></figure>


<ul>
<li>And add the following line to the end of the file which will make sure that the system will run our script in the login screen :</li>
</ul>


<figure class='code'><div class="highlight"><table><tr><td class="gutter"><pre class="line-numbers"><span class='line-number'>1</span>
</pre></td><td class='code'><pre><code class=''><span class='line'>display-setup-script=/usr/share/lightdmxrandr.sh</span></code></pre></td></tr></table></div></figure>


<ul>
<li>Finally, reboot your system!</li>
</ul>


<p>Got it fixed? Working perfectly? Great! Now, before thanking me, thank <a href="http://www.sudo-juice.com/lightdm-resolution/">sudo-juice.com</a> for coming up with a solution. In the script he used, he only fixed the resolution of the primary monitor. This will work for some but for people like me, it won&rsquo;t. I  had to fix the second monitor as well. The script I have given here can be used for any number of monitors! Hope it fixed your issues. If not, please leave a comment and let us know. We will try our best to fix it!</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[I Just Showed Windows 8 to a Friend : "Oh.. This is Not User Friendly"]]></title>
    <link href="http://techhamlet.com/2013/06/windows-8-is-not-user-friendly/"/>
    <updated>2013-06-08T20:59:42+05:30</updated>
    <id>http://techhamlet.com/2013/06/windows-8-is-not-user-friendly</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>When Microsoft first released Windows 8, I had my own doubts. I love new stuff but can I get used to Windows 8? I used it and thought I might be able to get used to it. I thought I liked it. But that&rsquo;s not the truth! I found out how I really felt about Windows 8 when I showed it to a friend today. As soon as he saw the new start screen, he said &#8221;Oh.. This is Not User Friendly. Windows 7 is way better!&ldquo;&hellip;</p>

<p>If I get a response like this from a novice user, it won&rsquo;t be a problem. It&rsquo;s really hard to find your way through Windows 8. But my friend is an Engineering student. He&rsquo;s not into IT much but still he know his stuff. He work with the computer everyday. He said its a mess. Full screen apps are ugly for him and problematic. Desktop without the start button is also a problem to him (Recently, Microsoft have confirmed that Windows 8.1 will have this start button back). I didn&rsquo;t told him that Windows 8 is also built for tablets. But he immediately said &ldquo;This is built like a tablet!&rdquo;.</p>

<p><img src="http://techhamlet.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/06/windows-8-550x309.jpg" alt="Windows 8" /> Windows 8</p>

<h3>It also became hard for him to find his way through Windows 8&hellip;</h3>

<p>Earlier we posted a video in our forum showing how a group of people presented <a href="http://techhamlet.com/forum/topic/66-it-took-this-mom-5-minutes-to-find-how-to-shutdown-windows-8-video/">Windows 8 to a novice user</a> and asked her to shut it down. It took a very long time for this novice user to find the shutdown button. When introducing Windows 8 to my friend, I showed him that there&rsquo;s a black bar that can be brought up by moving the mouse to the bottom right corner. I told him it have the shutdown option. But when I gave him my laptop, he again asked me where is the shutdown button? When I looked at the machine, he was pointing the mouse to the bottom right corner but there is no black bar! For a second, I was also stunned. Then when I did it my self I realized that we have to move the mouse to the corner and drag it upwards in-order to get the black bar. I&rsquo;m used to it so I didn&rsquo;t realize the problem. My friend used the new OS for some minutes and kept it aside saying &ldquo;Windows 7 is way better!&rdquo;.</p>

<h3>I realized that I also don&rsquo;t like the new Windows 8 that much&hellip;</h3>

<p>I thought I liked the new Windows 8. But I was wrong. When my friend asked me how I managed to live with it, I said, I&rsquo;m not using it that much! That&rsquo;s not my main OS! When Microsoft released Windows 7, I was using Linux as the main choise. But Windows 7 made me switch. I picked Windows 7 as my main OS. But after several years, I went back to Linux. With the release of Windows 8, again I switched and this time I was confident that I will make it my main OS. But actually, I didn&rsquo;t use it for long. I came back to Linux! Later, my Linux installation got extremely buggy and crashed all the time. Usually, I move to Windows in a time like this. But this time, I stayed with <a href="http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=uGzjjqHGAk8">Linux</a>.</p>

<p>Earlier I didn&rsquo;t realize that I don&rsquo;t like Windows 8 much. When thinking about my friend&rsquo;s review on 8, I started to think about what I really think about 8. Recently, people started to dump BIOS in favor of UEFI. I upgraded my PC and got a new Laptop. Both have UEFI now. In these systems, If I install Linux, it won&rsquo;t bring up the boot loader (once I wrote a post on <a href="http://techhamlet.com/2013/05/no-boot-loader-after-installing-ubuntu/">how to bring back the boot-loader</a> and <a href="http://techhamlet.com/2013/05/add-windows-to-grub/">add Windows 8</a>). Once I fixed this because I thought I wanted to switch operating systems daily like I did before. But later I ignored this. Of -course I can use the UEFI interface to switch OS. But its not easy. I had to press Esc or F10 every-time the system boot. If I mess up the timing, I have to reboot! But why did I ignored the boot loader issue? I didn&rsquo;t feel like going back to Windows. I had everything I wanted in Linux!</p>

<p>It&rsquo;s not hating Windows 8&hellip; It&rsquo;s because there are better options than 8. For my friend, he have Windows 7. For me, I have Linux! Can Windows 8 beat these two? I don&rsquo;t think so! What do you think?</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[How To Install Linux Mint : A Step by Step Guide and a Video Guide]]></title>
    <link href="http://techhamlet.com/2013/06/how-to-install-linux-mint/"/>
    <updated>2013-06-06T20:11:53+05:30</updated>
    <id>http://techhamlet.com/2013/06/how-to-install-linux-mint</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>First of all, I should mention that this guide is for complete Linux beginners. If you already have Linux experience, then figuring out how to install Linux Mint is a piece of cake. So, now, you are new to Linux. You might be here because Windows didn&rsquo;t match your tastes&hellip; You might be here because Mac doesn&rsquo;t match your tastes&hellip; No matter who you are, I will make sure that your first Linux Mint installation will go extremely smooth&hellip;</p>

<p>Linux Mint is the perfect desktop for beginners. It&rsquo;s not hard to grasp. The UI is extremely user-friendly and a user coming from Mac and Windows will be able to find his way through the new system with ease. So, you made the right decision.</p>

<h3>Questions you might have about installing Linux :</h3>

<p><strong>Will it prevent me from using Windows?</strong></p>

<p>No. If you follow the right steps, it won&rsquo;t harm your Windows installation. You can still use it with Linux.</p>

<p><strong>Will installing both Linux and Windows slow down my machine?</strong></p>

<p>Absolutely NO! You are installing Linux as a separate OS. When you run Linux, it will only load Linux to the memory. It won&rsquo;t even care about Windows. Same thing goes for Windows. They will act separately. So, no slowdowns. The only thing you will lose is disk space.</p>

<p><strong>Will it be hard to learn Linux? Is it ugly when compared to Windows? Do I always have to type commands?</strong></p>

<p>No, no and NO! Sometimes, Linux might be much easier to learn. It depends on the distribution you pick. The Linux Mint we choose is one of the most easiest to learn.</p>

<p>Linux now have the most beautiful interfaces. You can customize them in any way you like.</p>

<p>Many Linux people prefer to do their work using the command line (the terminal). But Linux have GUI tools to do almost anything a normal person wants. You might never touch the terminal. But if you get used to it, you&rsquo;ll feel its power and will always use it.</p>

<h3>Things you&rsquo;ll need to install Linux Mint :</h3>

<ul>
<li><p>x86 processor (Linux Mint 64-bit requires a 64-bit processor. Linux Mint 32-bit works on both 32-bit and 64-bit processors).</p></li>
<li><p>512 MB RAM (1GB recommended for a comfortable usage).</p></li>
<li><p>5 GB of disk space</p></li>
<li><p>Graphics card capable of 800×600 resolution</p></li>
<li><p>CD/DVD drive or USB port to install Linux Mint</p></li>
<li><p>Download the Linux Mint ISO from the official website : <a href="http://www.linuxmint.com/download.php">http://www.linuxmint.com/download.php</a> (Make sure you pick the right image. The Cinnamon version is recommended. If you have a new machine with a 64-bit processor (In Windows, right clicking Computer and checking properties will help you to find this) go for the 64-bit image. If you have an old machine with a 32-bit processor, go for the 32 bit version)</p></li>
<li><p>After downloading the ISO, burn it to a DVD or to a USB using <a href="http://www.pendrivelinux.com/universal-usb-installer-easy-as-1-2-3/">Pen Drive Linux</a> to install Linux Mint</p></li>
</ul>


<h3>For new machines with UEFI or Windows 8 :</h3>

<p>Before going to install Linux Mint , please read these articles :</p>

<ul>
<li><p><a href="http://techhamlet.com/2013/04/linux-with-uefi-choose-the-best-notebook/">Linux with UEFI and Windows 8 : How To Choose The Best Notebook to Buy</a></p></li>
<li><p><a href="http://techhamlet.com/2013/02/do-not-buy-windows-8-machines/">Linux and Windows Users Do Not Buy Windows 8 Machines : UEFI have Bugs</a></p></li>
</ul>


<h3>Now, lets Install Linux Mint &hellip;</h3>

<h4>The video guide :</h4>

<p>The video guide will give you a very good idea on what to do. For some, it will be more useful than the normal detailed guide. But I recommend you to follow both!</p>

<h4>The detailed guide :</h4>

<p><strong>1) Setting up BIOS/UEFI and booting the ISO :</strong></p>

<ul>
<li><p>First we need to make sure the BIOS will boot our installation media first to install Linux Mint. Insert the USB or the DVD intro the machine and boot it up. Press F2, F1, Delete, F8 or Esc keys during the boot (<strong>If you have a new machine based on the UEFI system, avoid pressing Esc or F8 keys and go to the UEFI system (Some still call it the BIOS)</strong>). To pick which key to press, you need to check your motherboard&rsquo;s manual.</p></li>
<li><p>If you have a UEFI system, go to the UEFI system and try to pinpoint the option name &ldquo;Secure Boot&rdquo;. If you locate it, disable it or set the option to &ldquo;Other OS&rdquo;. If you can&rsquo;t find it, proceed to install Linux Mint and hope that you don&rsquo;t have it.</p></li>
<li><p>If you go to the BIOS/UEFI system, go to the Boot menu and put the DVD ROM or the USB to the top of the boot list (Put the UEFI version to the top then the normal USB or the DVD. If the USB fail to boot with the UEFI, put the normal USB to the top and try again). Next, save and exit (Usually, its F10 to save and exit)</p></li>
<li><p>Now, some people will be taken to a boot menu where they&rsquo;ll see the available devices that can boot. (<strong>If you have a new machine based on the UEFI system, you need to reboot, avoid pressing Esc or F8 keys and go to the UEFI system (Some still call it the BIOS)</strong>) If you were taken to a boot menu, pick DVD ROM or the USB according to what you used. If you see an option called <strong>UEFI</strong> DVD or <strong>UEFI</strong> USB, pick that option (Sometimes, the USB won&rsquo;t boot with UEFI, so if it fail, reboot and pick the non UEFI option).</p></li>
</ul>


<p><strong>2) Testing and starting the installation :</strong></p>

<ul>
<li><p>If you successfully booted the disk, it will take you straight to the Linux Mint live desktop</p></li>
<li><p>Use this to test the new OS that you are going to install. Spend some time with it. Make sure you are confident with installing it on your machine</p></li>
<li><p>After you are completely confident about Linux Mint, click on &ldquo; <strong>Install Linux Mint</strong> &rdquo; icon in the desktop to start the installation wizard</p></li>
</ul>


<p><img src="http://techhamlet.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/06/install-linux-mint-550x309.jpg" alt="Install Linux Mint" /> Install Linux Mint</p>

<p><strong>3) The first steps of the installation wizard to install Linux Mint :</strong></p>

<ul>
<li><p>First, select your language and hit Continue</p></li>
<li><p>Next Mint will check whether you have a working internet connection and whether you have enough space on the disks to install Linux Mint</p></li>
<li><p>If everything is looking good, click continue</p></li>
</ul>


<p><strong>4) Partitioning (The most important part) :</strong></p>

<p>Also please refer to the video guide before attempting to create partitions!</p>

<p>Ok now we have come to the most important part. If you are not patient, if you doesn&rsquo;t have a single idea about what a partition is, please leave this page right now! You can&rsquo;t install Linux Mint without patience! If you are a newbie who don&rsquo;t know about partitions who have a clean system without any other operating system, you can stay! Read all the instructions in the sections before doing anything!</p>

<p><strong>If you have a clean system without any operating system installed :</strong></p>

<ul>
<li>In the &ldquo;Installation type&rdquo; window, select the default option &ldquo; <strong>Erase disk and install Linux Mint </strong>&rdquo;<strong> </strong>and click &ldquo;Install Now&rdquo; to install Linux Mint. (Next skip all the steps below and head directly to step 5)</li>
</ul>


<p><strong>If you have other operating systems on your machine :</strong></p>

<ul>
<li>Select &ldquo;Something Else&rdquo; and click &ldquo;Continue&rdquo;</li>
</ul>


<p><img src="http://techhamlet.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/06/install-linux-mint-partitioning-start-550x399.jpg" alt="Installation Type" /> Installation Type</p>

<p><strong>If your system have other partitions and doesn&rsquo;t have any free space :</strong></p>

<p>You can get some space from the last partition to install Linux Mint :</p>

<ul>
<li><p>To do this, click the last partition and click on &ldquo;Change&rdquo;</p></li>
<li><p>Now, in the size field, click on the minus button to reduce its space and click OK (<strong>Warning :</strong> to not reduce the size of the disk beyond the used space. If you have used 5GB in the 10GB hard drive. Do not shrink the drive&rsquo;s space to a value equal to or lower than 6GB! 7GB will be safe! Otherwise you will loose all your data!)</p></li>
<li><p>If it show a warning asking to &ldquo;Write previous changes to disk and continue&rdquo; click &ldquo;Continue&rdquo;</p></li>
</ul>


<p><img src="http://techhamlet.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/06/install-linux-mint-reduce-partition-size-550x422.jpg" alt="Reduce Partition Size" /> Reduce Partition Size</p>

<p>****You can delete the last partition if it doesn&rsquo;t have any stuff to install Linux Mint :</p>

<ul>
<li>Click on the minus button close to the Change button to delete the partition</li>
</ul>


<p><strong>If you already have free space or if you made some space available with the above methods, lets create the partitions to install Linux Mint :</strong></p>

<p><em>Note : If you have the free space in-between the existing partitions and if it&rsquo;s a new machine with UEFI and a GPT partition tablet, making the Linux partitions in this free space can raise some issues with the existing systems. So be careful.</em></p>

<p>Normally, we create three partitions. The root partition, the home partition and the swap partition. But you are free to create any number of partitions and assign mount points of your own. Today we are going to see how to create the three basic partitions&hellip;</p>

<ul>
<li>To create a partition, select the free space and click on the &ldquo;+&rdquo; sign</li>
</ul>


<p><strong>For the root partition :</strong></p>

<p>The root partition will hold all the system files and data&hellip;</p>

<ul>
<li><p>For the size of the root partition, the recommended size is about 10GB. But to be on the safe side, give at least 20GB (which will be nearly 20000MB. The field accept values in MB)</p></li>
<li><p>Leave the other parameters like the Type and the Location as it is</p></li>
<li><p>Change the field &ldquo;Use as&rdquo; to &ldquo;Ext4 journaling file system&rdquo;</p></li>
<li><p>Change the &ldquo;Mount point&rdquo; to &ldquo;<strong>/</strong>&rdquo;</p></li>
<li><p>Finally, click OK</p></li>
</ul>


<p><img src="http://techhamlet.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/06/install-linux-mint-root-partition-550x420.jpg" alt="Root Partition" /> Root Partition</p>

<p><strong>For the home partition :</strong></p>

<ul>
<li><p>For the size of the home partition, you can set any amount you like. Its going to hold all your personal data. Downloads, Documents, Videos, Pictures, the Desktop and even software configurations that are specific to you. Because of this, remember to give as much space as possible for this partition.</p></li>
<li><p>In here also, leave the parameters Type and Location intact and set the &ldquo;Use as&rdquo; field to &#8221;Ext4 journaling file system&#8221;</p></li>
<li><p>Now change the &ldquo;Mount point&rdquo; to &ldquo;/home&rdquo;</p></li>
<li><p>Click OK</p></li>
</ul>


<p><img src="http://techhamlet.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/06/install-linux-mint-home-partition-550x420.jpg" alt="Home Partition" /> Home Partition</p>

<p><strong>For the swap partition :</strong></p>

<p>The swap partition will act as a virtual memory. If your system doesn&rsquo;t have enough physical memory for the running programs, it will move inactive programs from the memory to the swap partition. If your system does a lot of swapping, things can get a bit slow because the hard drive is really slow when compared to the RAM. If your system doesn&rsquo;t have a lot of memory, then you need to pay extra attention to the swap partition. But for those who have a lot of RAM, you can have a small swap partition. I currently have 8GB of RAM in my desktop machine. The swap partition is 4GB. Currently, even though I run heavy applications like virtual box, the system haven&rsquo;t swapped anything.</p>

<ul>
<li><p>The size you need to give for a swap partition is a bit controversial. There are many theories for it. Some say you need a swap partition with the same size of your physical memory. Some say you need a swap partition double the size of the RAM. What I think is, if you have 4GB or less RAM, try to add the same size or the double if you have enough hard drive space. But if you have more than that, you can safely add the same size or a smaller size for swap. I use 4GB for 8GB of RAM.</p></li>
<li><p>In here also, leave the parameters Type and Location intact</p></li>
<li><p>Change the &ldquo;Use as&rdquo; field to &ldquo;swap area&rdquo;</p></li>
<li><p>And click OK</p></li>
</ul>


<p><img src="http://techhamlet.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/06/install-linux-mint-swap-partition-550x420.jpg" alt="Swap Partition" /> Swap Partition</p>

<p><strong>When you are done setting up the partitions :</strong></p>

<ul>
<li>Click &ldquo;Install Now&rdquo; to install Linux Mint</li>
</ul>


<p><strong>5) Selecting the time zone :</strong></p>

<ul>
<li><p>Now if you are connected to the internet, Linux Mint will automatically detect your location and select the time zone accordingly. But if its wrong, you are free to change it.</p></li>
<li><p>After you are done, click &ldquo;Continue&rdquo;</p></li>
</ul>


<p><strong>6) Select the Keyboard Layout :</strong></p>

<ul>
<li><p>Now, select the keyboard layout. If you don&rsquo;t know the layout you can use the box &ldquo;Type here to test your keyboard&rdquo; to detect it. For me, its &ldquo;English (US)&rdquo;</p></li>
<li><p>After you are done, click &ldquo;Continue&rdquo;</p></li>
</ul>


<p><strong>7) Setup your account and install Linux Mint :</strong></p>

<ul>
<li><p>Now, fill in your name</p></li>
<li><p>Your computer&rsquo;s name (Any name you like. No spaces, only digits, letters, hyphens and dots)</p></li>
<li><p>Give a username you want</p></li>
<li><p>If you don&rsquo;t want to enter the password every time you boot your machine, select &ldquo;Login automatically&rdquo; otherwise keep the default setting &ldquo;Require my password to login&rdquo;</p></li>
<li><p>If you don&rsquo;t want anyone to read your data without your password, select &ldquo;Encrypt my home folder&rdquo;. If you have any other Linux distribution on your machine, those systems can read your data. If some one take your hard drive and use a Linux Live CD, he can access your data. But if you encrypt it, no one can access them. Normally, I never use this because I need my other operating systems to read my data.</p></li>
<li><p>When you are done, click &ldquo;Continue&rdquo; to install Linux Mint</p></li>
</ul>


<p><img src="http://techhamlet.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/06/install-linux-mint-setup-account-550x420.jpg" alt="Setup Your Account" /> Setup Your Account</p>

<p><strong>8) After the installation is complete :</strong></p>

<ul>
<li><p>It will show a message saying the &ldquo;Installation is Complete&rdquo;. In here, click &ldquo;Restart Now&rdquo;</p></li>
<li><p>Make sure you remove the DVD or the USB that you used to install Linux Mint and hit enter to complete the installation!</p></li>
</ul>


<h3>If you have a new machine based on UEFI, please check these guides after you install Linux Mint :</h3>

<p>If you have other operating systems installed on your machine, you must check both these guides :</p>

<ul>
<li><p><a href="http://techhamlet.com/2013/05/no-boot-loader-after-installing-ubuntu/">No Boot loader After Installing Ubuntu! Linux with UEFI and Windows 8</a></p></li>
<li><p><a href="http://techhamlet.com/2013/05/add-windows-to-grub/">Add Windows to Grub Boot Loader : Linux with UEFI and Windows 8</a></p></li>
</ul>


<p><strong>Congratulation!</strong> Now you have installed one of the best Linux distributions on your machine. This might the first time you are using Linux. This might be the first time you are using Linux Mint. Still, I think you will enjoy the newly installed system. Isn&rsquo;t it better than the OS you used before? Share your thoughts with us as comments below. If you doesn&rsquo;t feel comfortable, don&rsquo;t worry, it will take some time to get adjusted to a new home.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Paranoid Android Halo : Taking Android Multi-Tasking To The Next Level]]></title>
    <link href="http://techhamlet.com/2013/06/paranoid-android-halo/"/>
    <updated>2013-06-05T21:12:13+05:30</updated>
    <id>http://techhamlet.com/2013/06/paranoid-android-halo</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>If you have already used the Paranoid Android ROM, then you already know that its one of the most innovative Android ROMs out there. The PA team have really cool ideas that no other Android ROM have ever thought of. First, they introduced the true hybrid mode. You can switch between, Tablet, Phablet and the Phone UIs without changing the system DPI, adding build.prop hacks or even without rebooting your device. <a href="http://www.paranoid-rom.com/">Paranoid Android</a> allows you to set the mode you want for each app. Each app can have its own mode. You can even change the title bar and nav bar colors for each app. You can also use their famous pie mode to go full screen. No status bar, no nav bar! How cool is that? Now, they are going another step forward by introducing Paranoid Android Halo !</p>

<p>Remember the key feature Facebook introduce with their latest messenger update? The chat heads? Chat heads will allow you to chat with your friends even while you are running another app. Without closing the existing app! Paranoid Android Halo is inspired by that. But it have more stuff&hellip;</p>

<h3>Paranoid Android Halo is not just for chatting&hellip;</h3>

<p>It will show any notification of any app. If you get a notification Paranoid Android Halo will show a small tooltip and fill its bubble with an image from the app. You don&rsquo;t have to stop the app you are currently working on. You don&rsquo;t have to lose its data. You don&rsquo;t have to stop the game you are playing&hellip; Simply click on Paranoid Android Halo and it will open what ever the app that generated the notification, let it be Gmail, Google Talk, Facebook, or any other app in a mini window in front of the existing app. The full app will be shown! after you are done dealing with the notification, you can click on the background and Halo will disappear! Android multi tasking to the next level! Check the video review created by <a href="http://www.youtube.com/user/oode?feature=watch">oode</a></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Advanced Mobile Care-A Must to Secure Your Android]]></title>
    <link href="http://techhamlet.com/2013/06/advanced-mobile-care-a-must-to-secure-your-android/"/>
    <updated>2013-06-04T08:05:22+05:30</updated>
    <id>http://techhamlet.com/2013/06/advanced-mobile-care-a-must-to-secure-your-android</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Advanced Mobile Care is an all-in-one Android security and performance optimization app that performs real-time virus scans while also featuring a brand new Anti-theft, powerful Game Speeder, Battery Saver, Call Blocker, App Manager, Task Killer, Privacy Locker, Privacy Advisor and Cloud Backup. Remember the world famous Advanced System care which take of your PC? Which clean, tweak, optimize and secure your PC? Advanced Mobile care is its Android version! A well trusted utility suit for Android.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Evernote for Linux : How to Use Evernote as a Normal Linux Desktop App]]></title>
    <link href="http://techhamlet.com/2013/06/evernote-for-linux/"/>
    <updated>2013-06-03T20:14:50+05:30</updated>
    <id>http://techhamlet.com/2013/06/evernote-for-linux</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Evernote is the king in online note taking apps. It&rsquo;s loved and used by many people around the world every day. Its full of features. You can use it to take simple notes, add to-do lists, save stuff to read leader and read them in a distraction free reader, clip items from the web, save important moments of your life, etc, etc, etc&hellip; Evernote stands out from the rest of the note taking apps because of its ease of use, huge number of features, many number of applications, killer unique features like searching words in the images you upload and the availability in almost any platform. You have Windows, Mac, Android, iOS, Blackberry, Windows Phone and Web apps built by Evernote. Unfortunately, there is no Evernote for Linux ! Linux users need to use the web client. But it can be painful to always go to the browser, enter the url, and then enter the log in information to use the service. But there&rsquo;s a shortcut&hellip;</p>

<p>There are some third-party apps like Everpad which bring Evernote for Linux. But there is a way to get to the official Evernote app right from your OS (With a desktop shortcut or through the system menu). It&rsquo;s a simple trick. But it works for many&hellip;</p>

<h3>How To add Evernote for Linux :</h3>

<p>Before proceeding, I should tell you that this is only a small trick. Sometimes, you might already know this trick. But haven&rsquo;t used it for real. But it will work&hellip;</p>

<p>What we are going to do is, install the Evernote Chrome web app. This will give you a full Evernote experience in Google Chrome. After log in in once, you don&rsquo;t need to log in again. One problem solved. Now we need a way to access it right from the desktop or through the menu without going through the browser. For this, Chrome have a solution! Here&rsquo;s how to get Evernote for Linux &hellip;</p>

<ul>
<li><p>First, open Google Chrome and install the <a href="https://chrome.google.com/webstore/detail/evernote-web/lbfehkoinhhcknnbdgnnmjhiladcgbol">Evernote web app</a></p></li>
<li><p>Now open a new tab and go to the web apps</p></li>
<li><p>Right click on Evernote (you can do this to any app) and select &ldquo;Create Shortcut&rdquo;</p></li>
</ul>


<p><img src="http://techhamlet.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/06/chrome-web-apps-550x312.jpg" alt="Evernote for Linux" /></p>

<ul>
<li><p>Now tick the places you need the shortcut to be added &ldquo;Desktop&rdquo; or &ldquo;Application Menu&rdquo; and click OK</p></li>
<li><p>Now you will get an Evernote icon on your desktop. You can use this to go directly to Evernote</p></li>
</ul>


<p>The shortcut will take you to a separate browser window which will open the Evernote web app. You have installed Evernote for Linux ! But this browser window won&rsquo;t have an address bar. Only Evernote. It&rsquo;s like an Evernote native app. But the only issue you will face is the absence of offline access. You need be connected to the Internet in order to use this. But today most of us always have a connection. So, for many this won&rsquo;t be a problem.</p>

<p>This might be the only way to get official app of Evernote for Linux. Lets hope that they&rsquo;ll understand the power of Linux in the future and create a native Linux app. Until then, this might work for you.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Add a Unity Like Dash to Gnome Desktop : No Need to go to the Overview]]></title>
    <link href="http://techhamlet.com/2013/05/dash-to-gnome-desktop/"/>
    <updated>2013-05-31T19:47:44+05:30</updated>
    <id>http://techhamlet.com/2013/05/dash-to-gnome-desktop</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="http://techhamlet.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/05/dash-to-dock-550x385.jpg" alt="Dash to Gnome" /></p>

<p>One of the biggest annoyances we have in Gnome Shell is the need to go to the overview by hovering the mouse over the top left corner of the screen every time we need to deal with open or new apps. In Unity, we always have the dash. In old systems, we always had the panel. To resolve the common issues in Gnome Shell, we have Shell Extensions. So, is there an extension that can save our lives? There is one good extension that can add a dash to Gnome desktop!</p>

<p>The Gnome Shell extension Dash to Dock will add a cool dash to Gnome desktop. Unlike the dash which comes out when you go to the overview, this dash won&rsquo;t hide itself in the desktop. It will hide only if you open a maximized app. Then it will hide to give space to the window. You also can edit this dash&rsquo;s settings to prevent it from hiding. You can even make it look exactly like Unity! A Unity Dash to Gnome desktop without installing Unity!</p>

<h3>How To add a Dash to Gnome desktop :</h3>

<ul>
<li><p>Open Chrome or Firefox and visit this URL : <a href="https://extensions.gnome.org/extension/307/dash-to-dock/">https://extensions.gnome.org/extension/307/dash-to-dock/</a></p></li>
<li><p>Now, simply, put the switch right next to the title of the extension to enable (switch on) the extension</p></li>
<li><p>To edit the settings of the dash, open the terminal and issue the following command :</p></li>
</ul>


<figure class='code'><div class="highlight"><table><tr><td class="gutter"><pre class="line-numbers"><span class='line-number'>1</span>
</pre></td><td class='code'><pre><code class=''><span class='line'>gnome-shell-extension-prefs dash-to-dock@micxgx.gmail.com</span></code></pre></td></tr></table></div></figure>


<p><img src="http://techhamlet.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/05/dash-to-dock-unity-550x309.jpg" alt="Dash to Gnome" /></p>

<p>There are plenty of settings for you to play with. But be careful about what you change. Remember that the Unity like Dash to Gnome is buggy. So, try your best to avoid using it. Most of the Gnome Shell users will gladly accept this Dash because many hate to waste time by always going to the overview. I really hated that and later came back to Ubuntu and Unity! So, try it and let me know what you think about the new Dash to Gnome extension!</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Linux Mint 15 is Released! The Most Ambitious Release Since the Start!]]></title>
    <link href="http://techhamlet.com/2013/05/linux-mint-15/"/>
    <updated>2013-05-30T20:02:44+05:30</updated>
    <id>http://techhamlet.com/2013/05/linux-mint-15</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="http://techhamlet.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/05/cinnamon-550x384.jpg" alt="Linux Mint 15" /> Linux Mint 15</p>

<p>The Linux Mint team have just finished building the 15th release of their famous Linux distribution and have finally announced the big release! Most of you waited for this moment since Ubuntu released their latest version in April. Now, Linux Mint 15 comes with more improvements and more new tools to help you!</p>

<p>Some people consider Linux Mint as the most easy to use beginner friendly OS in the planet. Some find it even easier than Windows and Mac. Its built on the famous Ubuntu. But Mint is a lot different from its mother. The Linux Mint team always tried to fix problems in Ubuntu. For example, Mint doesn&rsquo;t have the fancy Unity or Gnome Shell that confuse some users. It have its own desktop named Cinnamon and Mate which offer a much familiar and an easy to use look and feel. With the latest Linux Mint 15, things got even better!</p>

<p>The latest Linux Mint version is named Olivia. According to its developers, the latest Linux Mint 15 &ldquo;<strong><em>is the most ambitious release since the start of the project</em></strong>&rdquo;. The latest release has a lot of improvements to Cinnamon and Mate. Now, it have its own control center which can be used to customize a lot of aspects of your machine. Its more powerful than the default Gnome control center.</p>

<p>Linux Mint 15 also have a new display manager which use HTML5 themes. You can also use older themes but these new themes will be better looking and you can even add animations to them.</p>

<p>Olivia also have a new Software Sources which have more features than the Ubuntu version it used earlier. Now, you can also manage PPAs directly from the sources. Recently, Ubuntu merged the Driver Manager into the Software Sources. Now, Linux Mint 15 have separated them.</p>

<h3>Download Linux Mint 15 Now&hellip;</h3>

<p>Apart from these changes, there are a lot of small features and fixes. I haven&rsquo;t installed it yet. So, I only know what they told us in their official announcement. Now, <a href="http://www.linuxmint.com/download.php">download Linux Mint 15</a> and tell us what you think!</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Tech Know How : Have you got what it takes?]]></title>
    <link href="http://techhamlet.com/2013/05/tech-know-how-have-you-got-what-it-takes/"/>
    <updated>2013-05-30T18:59:09+05:30</updated>
    <id>http://techhamlet.com/2013/05/tech-know-how-have-you-got-what-it-takes</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Technical skill has become essential within business. It’s simple; the more ‘in the know’ you are about your field of work, the higher the chance you have of success. From <a href="http://www.talktalkbusiness.co.uk/products-and-services/voice-services/business-numbers/">call handling with Talk Talk</a> to internet services, it’s crucial for SMEs to familiarize themselves with the ins and outs. However, despite the direct correlation between greater knowledge and increased profit, enterprises are still not making technology an absolute priority.</p>

<p>In a recent investigation into the factors behind business growth, the results showed that up to 80% of SMEs recognize the importance of technology. Yet at the same time, 22% of those questioned also said that they need more technical expertise.[Footnote] This highlights the prevalent skills gap concerning companies, not to mention the reason why they’re not making the impact they hope on the market.</p>

<p>But how do you fair in the technical world? Here are the areas you need to consider.</p>

<p><img src="http://techhamlet.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/05/technology-550x385.jpg" alt="Technology" /> <em>Image source : <a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/pennstatelive/6680713953/">Penn State</a></em></p>

<h3>Cloud hosting</h3>

<p>A phrase that continues to crop up within the business world is cloud hosting. Allowing you to take control of your server, cloud hosting provides access to a virtual server in which previously stored software is held. In most case scenarios, only a small percentage of business servers are actually being used at one given time, wasting both money and resource. This is where cloud hosting helps. Enabling you to turn your virtual server on and off when you need to, your business  could really start to save money in the long run.</p>

<h3>Mobility</h3>

<p>Separate from business environments, it’s clear to see that modern society it getting mobile. From the incorporation of iPads within the workplace to the mass use of smartphones, mobility has proved to be indispensable when it comes to company success. In addition to wireless connections such as the previous, it’s also important that you evolve with other technologies. Invest in Business Grade features, and ensure that employees are comfortable in working with technologies such as fixed lines and data services.</p>

<h3>Connectivity</h3>

<p>Whilst the previous two areas can’t be ignored, at the same time it’s vital for businesses to maintain traditional means of communication, and to do this you need the best connectivity. The fact is, the internet is continually changing, so in order to keep ahead of the curve, you need to look to services that will increase its productivity even further. For example, products such as business broadband and Ethernet are simple ways to get your SME up to speed and performing to the highest quality.</p>

<p>1 Geared for Growth White Paper- <a href="http://www.talktalkbusiness.co.uk/Global/Final-Assets/Collateral/white_papers/Geared%20for%20Growth%20-%20Report.pdf">http://www.talktalkbusiness.co.uk/Global/Final-Assets/Collateral/white_papers/Geared%20for%20Growth%20-%20Report.pdf</a></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
