<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: web | Tech Hamlet]]></title>
  <link href="http://techhamlet.com/categories/web/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://techhamlet.com/"/>
  <updated>2014-01-05T10:46:34+05:30</updated>
  <id>http://techhamlet.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Pubudu Kodikara]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[SLT Will Increase Download Limits in 2014! But There's Some Bad News!]]></title>
    <link href="http://techhamlet.com/2014/01/new-slt-packages-for-2014/"/>
    <updated>2014-01-02T10:25:00+05:30</updated>
    <id>http://techhamlet.com/2014/01/new-slt-packages-for-2014</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>If you are living in <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Sri_Lanka">Sri Lanka</a> just like me, most probably you might be using Sri Lanka Telecom's broadband services. If you do, here's some good news for you... Starting from January 1 2014, <strong>SLT will add extra GBs to your broadband package!</strong> Now that's big news! A big gift from SLT! Here are the new package details :</p>

<p><img src="/images/post-images/2014/01/slt-new-packages.jpg" alt="SLT's New Packages" /></p>

<p>If you are an existing customer, you should get these new additions automatically.  You don't have to do anything! Great isn't it? Hold on... I said there's bad news... So whats the bad news?</p>

<p><a href="http://www.slt.lk/">SLT</a> is giving some extra GBs but there's a catch. .. There's always a catch! Earlier, in their package descriptions they mentioned about separate off peak and peak download limits. For example, if they say you are going to get 35 GB per month, it will be 25 GB for peak hours and 10 GB for off peak hours. Earlier, this didn't work. For both peak and off peak we got 35 GB. But now things are going to change...</p>

<p>Now, the peak and off peak limits will be calculated separately! So in the new packages, you will get your old bandwidth limits for peak hours. <strong>The extra GBs will be for off peak!</strong> If you run out of your peak limit, your connection will be slowed down to 64 Kbps during the peak hours. Same theory will be applied for off peak. There's one good thing... Earlier, the off peak time is from 12 AM to 6 AM. That's ridiculous. Most of us are sleeping at that time and we will never use the off peak bandwidth. But now, they have extended this time to 8 AM! That's really good. But still for businesses this won't help. Most people open at 8 AM.</p>

<p>There's another small problem... Did you notice the new and improved usage monitor of SLT? It's a really good move. But it also have a catch... Earlier, smart people used to wait till the end of the month and start downloading everything they need because the usage meter takes some time to update and when it updates, we have already downloaded way over the limit! But I don't think it will work now... <strong>The new usage meter seems to be updating almost instantly :(</strong></p>

<p>Its OK to limits bandwidth like this because I have seen how people download. In Sri Lanka there's no law to limit torrenting. So people fill their hard drives with films and games. They buy more drives just for downloads! Thats crazy! The ISPs don't have a chance here. But what I'm saying is that the limits they have added now are too much. Im a web developer and when compared to other countries, I have to pay a huge amount of money to get enough bandwidth for my day today work!</p>

<p>So, just because Sri Lanka Telecom gave you extra GBs to download, don't go and download like crazy
... We know who they are... SLT won't give something without a hidden catch... You already know that it have the worst reputation in the country. .. So be careful!</p>

<p><strong>Update :</strong> Please note that I didn't tell anyone to bend the rules. Im saying not to do it because many people used to skip the rules and go over the limits. But Im telling everyone to stop because (yes its not right) you can't do it anymore! I didn't even said the new changes are good <strong>A big gift from SLT</strong> and I ment it! Apart from the changes they mention, there are some things that you people need to know and thats why I wrote this post.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
