<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Windows | Tech Hamlet]]></title>
  <link href="http://techhamlet.com/categories/windows/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://techhamlet.com/"/>
  <updated>2013-08-03T20:56:00+05:30</updated>
  <id>http://techhamlet.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Pubudu Kodikara]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Bitdefender 2014 is Released! Its Faster, Lighter and More Secure!]]></title>
    <link href="http://techhamlet.com/2013/06/bitdefender-2014-released/"/>
    <updated>2013-06-26T21:22:14+05:30</updated>
    <id>http://techhamlet.com/2013/06/bitdefender-2014-released</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="http://techhamlet.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/06/bitdefender2014-550x385.jpg" alt="Bitdefender 2014" /> Bitdefender 2014</p>

<p>Folks at Bitdefender have just released a major upgrade to their security suits! The new Bitdefender 2014 is now available for everyone! Bitdefender started to test this new version a bit earlier than in the previous years. They released the first <a href="http://techhamlet.com/2013/03/bitdefender-2014-beta/">public beta</a> version on March. After testing for about 4 months, they have just released the new security suit today.</p>

<h3>Bitdefender 2014&hellip;</h3>

<p><a href="http://www.bitdefender.com/solutions/internet-security.html">Bitdefender 2014</a> &rsquo;s main point is speed. According to Bitdefender, their new photon technology will make things a lot lighter. That means, the anti virus will be a lot faster! Not only the anti virus, even the whole system will be faster. Normally, an anti virus can significantly slow down a computer. Some people don&rsquo;t even use anti virus apps for this reason. But with this new technology, Bitdefender 2014 might change the way how people think about security suits.</p>

<p>Apart from the speed, there are a lot of security enhancements, enhancements to<a href="http://techhamlet.com/2013/06/bitdefender-safepay/"> safepay</a>, cloud anti spam and some new features. The developers have also changed the look and feel of the app. Now its even more smoother. Will glide through your system smoothly protecting every corner of it!</p>

<p>Currently, according to independent lab tests, Bitdefender is the number one security suit on the planet. If you read of blog earlier, you should know this. That&rsquo;s why we always follow their products. Recently, they have also gained the crown in Android security which was earlier held by Trust Go. Now, if you already have Bitdefender, you can install this new version free of charge. If you want to buy it, please wait. We might hold a free giveaway of Bitdefender 2014 ! Want to grab a free key to this awesome security suit? Just be patient and wait&hellip; Also if you need to learn more on this new Bitdefender, wait for my full review.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Bitdefender Safepay : A More Secure Browser for Your Critical Work!]]></title>
    <link href="http://techhamlet.com/2013/06/bitdefender-safepay/"/>
    <updated>2013-06-17T20:41:28+05:30</updated>
    <id>http://techhamlet.com/2013/06/bitdefender-safepay</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="http://techhamlet.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/06/safepay-550x412.jpg" alt="Bitdefender Safepay" /> Bitdefender Safepay</p>

<p>If you are banking online, buying things from an online store or doing other critical stuff like this, many people will try their best to get their hand on your details. Your credit card information, the passwords, user names, emails, these stuff can ruin your life if they go to the wrong hands. But, the problem is, the Internet is full of these hands trying to grab your data. Is there a way to get rid of them? You can&rsquo;t get rid of every threat, but Bitdefender Safepay will help you stay away from most of them!</p>

<p>Bitdefender is the number one security suit in the industry and they have kept that place for years. Recently, they introduced a cool new feature in their security suit named Bitdefender Safepay. It is a browser. But not an ordinary one. Its more secure. A normal browser doesn&rsquo;t enforce all the security features because it will slow down the normal browsing. But Bitdefender Safepay have them enabled.</p>

<p>First of all, it will scan your machine for threats and warn you if there&rsquo;s something wrong. If there&rsquo;s something that can tap your data and ruin your life. Then, when you deal with online banks, stores and other critical sites, it will secure your whole connection, and the browser environment you are working. It will isolate the browser from the rest of the system and make sure no one can tap into it. It also have a virtual keyboard which can be used to prevent keyloggers from logging your data and sending them to the hackers! Bitdefender Safepay can also protect you from unsecured Wi-Fi connections by securing the whole connection. Normally, if you use an unsecured public hot spot, there are a lot of chances that your data might get hacked. But <a href="http://www.bitdefender.com/media/html/beta-safepay/index.html">Bitdefender Safepay</a> can rescue you.</p>

<p>Bitdefender offered all these cool features as an add-on in their security suit. So, you need to install Bitdefender in order to get this functionality. But Bitdefender doesn&rsquo;t want to keep it only for their own customers. They are getting ready to release it to every one! Now even if you don&rsquo;t have Bitdefender, you can install Bitdefender Safepay Beta and use the highly secured browser for your critical work!</p>

<p>The product is still in beta stage and might have some bugs. But still its worth trying out because the <a href="http://youarecurio.us/2013/05/internet-is-evil/">internet is getting dangerous</a> everyday! Bitdefender have also organized a small contest where they will give fabulous prizes to those who help them test their beta product! Download and try Bitdefender Safepay now!</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[I Just Showed Windows 8 to a Friend : "Oh.. This is Not User Friendly"]]></title>
    <link href="http://techhamlet.com/2013/06/windows-8-is-not-user-friendly/"/>
    <updated>2013-06-08T20:59:42+05:30</updated>
    <id>http://techhamlet.com/2013/06/windows-8-is-not-user-friendly</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>When Microsoft first released Windows 8, I had my own doubts. I love new stuff but can I get used to Windows 8? I used it and thought I might be able to get used to it. I thought I liked it. But that&rsquo;s not the truth! I found out how I really felt about Windows 8 when I showed it to a friend today. As soon as he saw the new start screen, he said "Oh.. This is Not User Friendly. Windows 7 is way better!&ldquo;&hellip;</p>

<p>If I get a response like this from a novice user, it won&rsquo;t be a problem. It&rsquo;s really hard to find your way through Windows 8. But my friend is an Engineering student. He&rsquo;s not into IT much but still he know his stuff. He work with the computer everyday. He said its a mess. Full screen apps are ugly for him and problematic. Desktop without the start button is also a problem to him (Recently, Microsoft have confirmed that Windows 8.1 will have this start button back). I didn&rsquo;t told him that Windows 8 is also built for tablets. But he immediately said &ldquo;This is built like a tablet!&rdquo;.</p>

<p><img src="http://techhamlet.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/06/windows-8-550x309.jpg" alt="Windows 8" /> Windows 8</p>

<h3>It also became hard for him to find his way through Windows 8&hellip;</h3>

<p>Earlier we posted a video in our forum showing how a group of people presented <a href="http://techhamlet.com/forum/topic/66-it-took-this-mom-5-minutes-to-find-how-to-shutdown-windows-8-video/">Windows 8 to a novice user</a> and asked her to shut it down. It took a very long time for this novice user to find the shutdown button. When introducing Windows 8 to my friend, I showed him that there&rsquo;s a black bar that can be brought up by moving the mouse to the bottom right corner. I told him it have the shutdown option. But when I gave him my laptop, he again asked me where is the shutdown button? When I looked at the machine, he was pointing the mouse to the bottom right corner but there is no black bar! For a second, I was also stunned. Then when I did it my self I realized that we have to move the mouse to the corner and drag it upwards in-order to get the black bar. I&rsquo;m used to it so I didn&rsquo;t realize the problem. My friend used the new OS for some minutes and kept it aside saying &ldquo;Windows 7 is way better!&rdquo;.</p>

<h3>I realized that I also don&rsquo;t like the new Windows 8 that much&hellip;</h3>

<p>I thought I liked the new Windows 8. But I was wrong. When my friend asked me how I managed to live with it, I said, I&rsquo;m not using it that much! That&rsquo;s not my main OS! When Microsoft released Windows 7, I was using Linux as the main choise. But Windows 7 made me switch. I picked Windows 7 as my main OS. But after several years, I went back to Linux. With the release of Windows 8, again I switched and this time I was confident that I will make it my main OS. But actually, I didn&rsquo;t use it for long. I came back to Linux! Later, my Linux installation got extremely buggy and crashed all the time. Usually, I move to Windows in a time like this. But this time, I stayed with <a href="http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=uGzjjqHGAk8">Linux</a>.</p>

<p>Earlier I didn&rsquo;t realize that I don&rsquo;t like Windows 8 much. When thinking about my friend&rsquo;s review on 8, I started to think about what I really think about 8. Recently, people started to dump BIOS in favor of UEFI. I upgraded my PC and got a new Laptop. Both have UEFI now. In these systems, If I install Linux, it won&rsquo;t bring up the boot loader (once I wrote a post on <a href="http://techhamlet.com/2013/05/no-boot-loader-after-installing-ubuntu/">how to bring back the boot-loader</a> and <a href="http://techhamlet.com/2013/05/add-windows-to-grub/">add Windows 8</a>). Once I fixed this because I thought I wanted to switch operating systems daily like I did before. But later I ignored this. Of -course I can use the UEFI interface to switch OS. But its not easy. I had to press Esc or F10 every-time the system boot. If I mess up the timing, I have to reboot! But why did I ignored the boot loader issue? I didn&rsquo;t feel like going back to Windows. I had everything I wanted in Linux!</p>

<p>It&rsquo;s not hating Windows 8&hellip; It&rsquo;s because there are better options than 8. For my friend, he have Windows 7. For me, I have Linux! Can Windows 8 beat these two? I don&rsquo;t think so! What do you think?</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Discover Windows 8 App Sizes]]></title>
    <link href="http://techhamlet.com/2013/05/discover-windows-8-app-sizes/"/>
    <updated>2013-05-09T20:04:06+05:30</updated>
    <id>http://techhamlet.com/2013/05/discover-windows-8-app-sizes</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="http://techhamlet.com/wp-content/uploads/2012/12/windows8-550x309.jpg" alt="Windows 8" /></p>

<p>Everyone using Windows 8 might have thought to themselves at least for once and might have put that thought away &ldquo;Wonder where are the App Sizes&rdquo;. Don&rsquo;t worry peeps this problem can be solved and you are on the right track reading this article.</p>

<p>The Windows Store lets you browse and install apps that you can then run from the start page of the operating system. If you want to clean up your PC and remove the clutter to free up drive space, it makes sense to remove the biggest programs first. With Windows 8, though, there isn&rsquo;t an obvious way to find out how big its Start Screen Apps are. While this may not be a problem as many of the apps do not cross the 100mb mark but, if you think about Microsoft&rsquo;s upcoming Surface RT device, you will notice that it only ships with 32 Gigabytes of storage for the operating system and data. The same can be true for systems where Windows is installed on a Solid State Drive, as it appears that apps get automatically installed on the Windows drive with no option to install them elsewhere.</p>

<h3>Display the size of Windows 8 apps</h3>

<p>What you need to do is to move the mouse to the right of the screen to show the Charms (or press Windows + C ) and click Settings. Then click the &lsquo;Change PC Settings&rsquo; and select General on the left. Under the &lsquo;Available Storage&rsquo; heading click &lsquo;View app sizes&rsquo;, and all the Start Screen Apps and their sizes are listed. You can then see which ones are the biggest and which will release more drive space.</p>

<p>To uninstall apps, right-click them on the Start Screen and select Uninstall at the bottom.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Microsoft Musn't Neglect Windows 7 Users]]></title>
    <link href="http://techhamlet.com/2013/04/microsoft-neglect-windows-7/"/>
    <updated>2013-04-22T20:00:36+05:30</updated>
    <id>http://techhamlet.com/2013/04/microsoft-neglect-windows-7</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="http://techhamlet.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/04/windows7-550x385.jpg" alt="Windows 7" /> <em>Image Source : <a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/pixelydixel/4033946329/">Jonan Basterra</a></em></p>

<p>So after just 6 months Microsoft is planning to update 8, even though most people have barely got used to its pretty colored tiles and where&rsquo;s the Start Menu interface. Thats all very well for those who use Windows 8 and whose only desire is to have the most cutting-edge PC possible, but Microsoft seems to forget that millions of us are there who don&rsquo;t.</p>

<p>I finally upgraded from Windows XP to Windows 7 this year, for the sole reason that my XP machine had given up the ghost and I needed a new one. I was otherwise perfectly happy with XP, but soon got to grips with 7, once I figured out where everything was.</p>

<p>My big fear is that with every new PC and laptop running 8,and this Windows Blue thing adding new bells and whistles to that operating system, Microsoft is neglecting its Windows 7, XP and Vista users. We paid good money for these older OS, so why should we feel obliged to fork out again. I would like to see the company release updates for users who don&rsquo;t use 8 other than dull but necessary Service Packs.</p>

<p>I need only point to the case of <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Internet_Explorer_10">IE 10</a> which has only now reached Windows 7 after being available for Windows 8 since last October, and which won&rsquo;t work at all in Windows Vista and XP.</p>

<p>In my opinion Microsoft should treat all its customers fairly, rather than giving preference to those who have bought its newest products.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
