<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: android | Tech Hamlet]]></title>
  <link href="http://techhamlet.com/categories/android/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://techhamlet.com/"/>
  <updated>2014-06-06T16:05:48+00:00</updated>
  <id>http://techhamlet.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Pubudu Kodikara]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Drippler : The Best Way to Learn All About Your Android Device!]]></title>
    <link href="http://techhamlet.com/2014/01/drippler/"/>
    <updated>2014-01-02T17:58:00+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://techhamlet.com/2014/01/drippler</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>If you have an Android device, trust me when I say this&hellip; You still have a lot to learn about your little device! Android is not like any other smart phone OS. It&rsquo;s full of cool features. There are a lot of cool apps for you to discover&hellip; Everyday something new and exiting happen in the Android community which you should know! So, how to keep track of all these things?</p>

<p>There are many news reading apps for <a href="http://techhamlet.com/categories/android/">Android</a> but <a href="http://drippler.com/">Drippler</a> is different. It only give you Android stuff! It will give  you top Android news everyday&hellip; Top or newly discovered cool Android apps for you to try&hellip; Articles with tips and tricks&hellip; And many more&hellip;</p>

<p><img src="/images/post-images/2014/01/drippler-shot.jpg" alt="Drippler" /></p>

<p>On the first run, Drippler will detect your device and let you change it if it&rsquo;s wrong. So, thereafter you will get most of the stuff targeting your own device!</p>

<p>Drippler is unique. It&rsquo;s not built as another news reading app. It&rsquo;s soul purpose is to help you discover more about your device and the Android world. The tech world is changing every second so you should have an app like this to keep up with it!</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
