<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: others | Tech Hamlet]]></title>
  <link href="http://techhamlet.com/categories/others/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://techhamlet.com/"/>
  <updated>2014-01-05T10:13:04+05:30</updated>
  <id>http://techhamlet.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Pubudu Kodikara]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Best and the Worst Sri Lankan Computer Stores of 2013]]></title>
    <link href="http://techhamlet.com/2014/01/sri-lankan-tech-vendors-2013/"/>
    <updated>2014-01-05T08:40:00+05:30</updated>
    <id>http://techhamlet.com/2014/01/sri-lankan-tech-vendors-2013</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>In Sri Lanka its a bit hard to find a good shop to buy tech stuff. People mostly visit Colombo to buy Computers, Laptops and other gadgets... There are a lot of cheap stores out there... Many sell crap. You can find the same product elsewhere but the inside is different.  Some sellers deal with cheap crappy manufacturers. Many don't give a good after sale service. If you go for warranty there's a good chance you'll come back empty handed! So how can we avoid these issues and get what we want? Let me help... In this post I'm going to list some popular shops in SL and review them... I can write only about the shops that I have visited. So, if you want to add to the list, please leave a comment!</p>

<p><img src="/images/post-images/2014/01/shop.jpg" alt="Computer Store" /></p>

<h2><a href="http://www.barclays.lk/">Barclays (Excellent)</a></h2>

<p>The first place goes to Barclays. They are well known for their quality and good after sales support. Sometimes you can find the same product for a cheaper price in another shop from a different manufacturer. Trust me... You don't want to go for the cheap one. There's a reason why Barclays stay away from some manufacturers. It's because they are faulty! Their after sales support is also really good. But not perfect because they still don't know how to smile at the customer (I'm talking about after sales support)</p>

<h2><a href="http://mcentre.lk/">Metropolitan (Excellent)</a></h2>

<p>My experience with Metropolitan is good... But I still recommend them. They know really well how to handle the customers. Both sales and after sales. You can't find more friendlier people than these guys in any other store. They always respond with a smile even when you go for warranty several times! I really like that place. If you need to buy a laptop, a desktop (a branded one), quality accessories, a good phone... You can visit them. They are the Acer agents in Si Lanka. I think they also directly deal with Sony. I went there first to buy a laptop. But on the first day it started to show a lot of trouble. We can't blame Metropolitan because the real problem is with the manufacturer... HP.  Every machine in that model was faulty. I wrote about this issues once and told everyone to <a href="http://techhamlet.com/2013/03/stay-away-from-hp/">stay away from HP products</a>. Metropolitan handled the case really well... Got the machine back and returned my money with a smile. You should try them first!</p>

<h2><a href="http://www.epsi.lk/">Epsi (Good)</a></h2>

<p>I don't know about their after sales support because I didn't got a chance to get that support.  I bought a laptop and a motherboard from them and still didn't face any issues! They are the agents for Asus so if you need to buy a really solid laptop that can last long, go for them. They also do Apple products! So, Apple lovers... go for Epsi.</p>

<h2><a href="http://laptop.lk/">Laptop.lk (Not Good)</a></h2>

<p>They say they are the best place to buy a laptop in Sri Lanka but I say stay away from them at all costs. Laptop.lk have a really good selection. I don't think you'll need to fear about changed parts because once I bought a HP laptop from them and the HP people accepted the machine for warranty.  They won't accept it if the parts are changed.  The problem is with the after sales support. They'll tell you to go to that floor then the other floor and finally they'll tell you to go and meet the manufacturer! Stay away from them!</p>

<h2><a href="http://www.techinfo.lk/techzone.html">TechZone (Bad)</a></h2>

<p>They might be good for small things like keyboards and mice but they have a bad reputation when it comes to big products. My experience with them is not good... Once I tried to buy a graphic card. I bought it from these guys. As soon as I install the drivers for the card it started to scream like hell. I contacted the manufacturer online and they said it's faulty.  The shop didn't believe me. It was really hard to take my money back but finally I did.</p>

<p>And I should say this... TechZone's after sales support team is horrible. I think I went their at about 9.30 AM. All the other shops are open. These guys are just opening.  One man checked my graphic card and asked me to wait till another guy come to work. It was way past 10.00 AM when that guy arrived. He again told me to wait till they fetch another similar card and the guy who just came to work just wondered off the office with his phone... After a long time the guy who went to fetch the card came back but the guy who test it is out (wondered off)! I had to spend several hours waiting to get my job done and by the time I'm done, I'm fully exhausted! I had one question... Does the managers really pay these guys to wonder off at work hours ignoring the customers? They hardly do any work!</p>

<p>People also complain In forums saying these guys replace laptop parts with cheap ones. The manufacturer won't give you any warranty for them. I don't know whether this is true so please note it... Earlier they said they were authorized dealers of HP but HP made an announcement in a local newspaper saying these guys are lying! But now I think they have registered with HP. I would stay away from them at all costs!</p>

<h3>The list is not finished!</h3>

<p>This list is not complete. I wrote only about the shops that I have tried. So, readers... you have to complete the rest. Write about your favorite shop or about the most horrible place you have ever visited in the comments below!</p>

<h3>Final words...</h3>

<p>Even though you visit the top vendors in this list, don't let them make the selection for you. We can trust the vendors but not all the manufacturers they deal with. So do your research online, check reviews, pick the product you want to buy and then go and buy it. If the product is something small like a mouse or a keyboard, you can get it from anywhere you want! Always be-careful!</p>

<p><em>-Top image source : <a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/lemon/33224803/">Chris Enns</a></em></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Wish You all a Very Happy New Year! How Did You Spent it?]]></title>
    <link href="http://techhamlet.com/2014/01/happy-new-year-2014/"/>
    <updated>2014-01-01T18:18:00+05:30</updated>
    <id>http://techhamlet.com/2014/01/happy-new-year-2014</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>We have just left 2013 and now stepping into 2014! Its a new year. Everyone have their own unique way to celebrate the new year. Make sure you spend it in a meaningful way...</p>

<p><img src="/images/post-images/2014/01/new-year-2014.jpg" alt="Happy New Year" /></p>

<p>You know what... Here's what I did for the new year... On the 31st of December, I took my phone, went to the balcony and started making a list...</p>

<p><a href="http://instagram.com/p/iVYZPaKogx/"><img src="/images/post-images/2014/01/my-balcony.jpg" alt="Thats my Balcony!" /></a></p>

<p>I listed all the mistakes I made in 2013. I wrote down how I am going to fix them! Then I set some goals for the upcoming year. When I'm done with the review, I went to bed!  In the morning, I woke up like a new born baby... I wanted to forget about the past and face the new year with a refreshed mind! You should not bring the past junk to the new year. Leave it behind. Only bring what you learnt from the past year. Make sure the new year is better than the past year!</p>

<p>What do you think? Isn't it a good way to face the new year? How did you spend it? Share with us!</p>

<p>We are now stepping into a brand new year... So, what kind of posts do you want from us this year? Let us know what you want and we shall give it to you!</p>

<h1>Happy New Year Everyone!</h1>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
