<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Others | Tech Hamlet]]></title>
  <link href="http://techhamlet.com/categories/others/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://techhamlet.com/"/>
  <updated>2013-09-29T13:29:30+05:30</updated>
  <id>http://techhamlet.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Pubudu Kodikara]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Does the iPhone 6 Represent the Future?]]></title>
    <link href="http://techhamlet.com/2013/06/iphone-6-represent-the-future/"/>
    <updated>2013-06-17T20:16:38+05:30</updated>
    <id>http://techhamlet.com/2013/06/iphone-6-represent-the-future</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Although there is still no official word from Apple about the latest iPhone incarnation, several creative individuals continue to come up with some unique design and concept ideas to get the public’s imagination racing.</p>

<p>In the past we have seen built-in projectors, virtual laser keyboards and even 3D cameras. However, this latest concept combines technology that is currently available with innovations that every Smartphone manufacturer strives for.</p>

<p><img src="http://techhamlet.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/06/iphone6-550x385.jpg" alt="iPhone 6" /> <em>Image Source : <a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/thronx/8008932080/">thronx</a></em></p>

<h3>Water-resistant and dustproof</h3>

<p>Even though the iPhone 5 has shown itself to be fairly resistant to water in recent consumer tests, this concept takes inspiration from other Smartphones available on the market.</p>

<p>Sony's Experia Z, released in February 2013, has Ingress Protection Ratings of IP55 and IP57, making it dustproof and water-resistant. Able to deal with one metre of water for up to thirty minutes, the Experia Z is one of the world&rsquo;s toughest Smartphones.</p>

<p>Last year, speculation suggested that Apple was working on a water-resistant coating for its products, meaning such protection from the elements would be a distinct possibility. However, with full control over its component supply chain, Apple might be content with the money it makes from repairs.</p>

<h3>Wireless charging</h3>

<p>In what is considered by several commentators to be the holy grail of technological progress, this iPhone 6 concept also manages to achieve wireless charging.</p>

<p>Even with some great <a href="http://www.buymobilephones.net/mobile-phones/apple">Apple iPhone deals</a> available, messy cables and tangled wires have been one of the most frustrating aspects about owning a Smartphone. Manufacturers including Nokia, LG and HTC have all recently championed the technology, but there has yet to be any solid inductive charging evidence from Apple.</p>

<p>However, when you consider that Samsung&rsquo;s Galaxy S4, the iPhone&rsquo;s main smartphone rival, now supports wireless charging, it certainly makes sense for Apple to pursue the technology.</p>

<h3>Other notable features</h3>

<p>Additional innovations include touch-sensitive casing and LED notifications, taking influence from some recent Apple patents.</p>

<p>Although LED notifications on either side of the casing is a novel idea, current iPhone users already have this option via the camera&rsquo;s flashlight. Up until now, Apple has favoured physical buttons. However, there are various aesthetic and design advantages to touch-sensitive controls.</p>

<p>It remains to be seen whether the iPhone 6 will include these advances. However, with rival Smartphones already featuring such additions, Apple should certainly take note.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Firefox OS to Launch on Foxconn Tablets]]></title>
    <link href="http://techhamlet.com/2013/06/firefox-os-launch-on-foxconn/"/>
    <updated>2013-06-15T20:32:54+05:30</updated>
    <id>http://techhamlet.com/2013/06/firefox-os-launch-on-foxconn</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://techhamlet.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/06/Firefox-OS_tablet_610x416.jpg"><img src="http://techhamlet.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/06/Firefox-OS_tablet_610x416-300x204.jpg" alt="Firefox OS to launch on Foxconn tablets" /></a> Firefox OS to launch on Foxconn tablets</p>

<p>Firefox is ready to launch their OS soon this summer.
<strong>
</strong></p>

<h3><strong>What Happened?</strong></h3>

<p>Browser developer Mozilla and hardware manufacturer Foxconn signed a deal to create devices running open-source mobile OS. Mozilla had already signed up smartphone makers to use its OS on their handsets. Foxconn is a Chinese manufacturer that produces hardware for a host of big tech companies, including Apple.</p>

<p><strong>
</strong></p>

<h3><strong>How will it affect you? The Firefox OS</strong></h3>

<p>This is a big win if you&rsquo;re a Firefox fan and could help propel the new operating system onto other devices. This OS focuses on HTML rather than apps, which means for example you can use the Facebook mobile site rather than download an app. It also has strong privacy controls. The Firefox OS tablets will offer a competitive alternative to Google and Apple devices.</p>

<p><strong>
</strong></p>

<h3><strong>What does Techhamlet think about Firefox OS?</strong></h3>

<p>This is Foxconns first big move into making its own branded hardware and that&rsquo;s big news for Firefox. We think it will give Mozilla a head start in the Chinese market and could lead to other hardware makers adopting the software.</p>

<blockquote><p>If Foxconn&rsquo;s tablets are a success then Firefox OS will be too</p></blockquote>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[BBM Coming To Android]]></title>
    <link href="http://techhamlet.com/2013/06/bbm-coming-to-android/"/>
    <updated>2013-06-15T20:31:42+05:30</updated>
    <id>http://techhamlet.com/2013/06/bbm-coming-to-android</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://techhamlet.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/06/bbm.jpg"><img src="http://techhamlet.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/06/bbm-300x176.jpg" alt="Blackberry Messenger BBM coming to Android this summer" /></a> Blackberry Messenger BBM coming to Android this summer</p>

<blockquote><p>The once venerable messaging service BBM makes its belated move to Android this summer.</p></blockquote>

<p>Blackberry has announced that its flagship BBM will be coming to Android this summer. It will be available as a free download from the Play Store, and will compete with the likes of Google&rsquo;s new Hangouts app, Facebook Home and WhatsApp in the battle to dominate the mobile messaging space.</p>

<blockquote><p>The move to make BBM cross platform was first mooted two years ago</p>

<p>It will also be available for iOS</p></blockquote>

<p>Blackberry was the market leader in messaging and ranked among the worlds biggest smartphone manufacturers. Today the company&rsquo;s share stands at less than 3% and falling. The same figures put Android&rsquo;s share at a whopping 75%.</p>

<p>Messaging is increasingly becoming one of the key battlegrounds in the mobile, and is seen as one of the best ways to lock users into a particular platform. Meanwhile &lsquo;over the top&rsquo; messaging apps are plentiful. It&rsquo;s into this crowded market that BBM is making its move. The brand may be diminished and the decision may appear to be a last resort for Blackberry, but the app and service are still more than competitive and fondly remembered by many of its past users. That should at least guarantee a certain level of interest in the app when it arrives this summer.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Tech Know How : Have you got what it takes?]]></title>
    <link href="http://techhamlet.com/2013/05/tech-know-how-have-you-got-what-it-takes/"/>
    <updated>2013-05-30T18:59:09+05:30</updated>
    <id>http://techhamlet.com/2013/05/tech-know-how-have-you-got-what-it-takes</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Technical skill has become essential within business. It’s simple; the more ‘in the know’ you are about your field of work, the higher the chance you have of success. From <a href="http://www.talktalkbusiness.co.uk/products-and-services/voice-services/business-numbers/">call handling with Talk Talk</a> to internet services, it’s crucial for SMEs to familiarize themselves with the ins and outs. However, despite the direct correlation between greater knowledge and increased profit, enterprises are still not making technology an absolute priority.</p>

<p>In a recent investigation into the factors behind business growth, the results showed that up to 80% of SMEs recognize the importance of technology. Yet at the same time, 22% of those questioned also said that they need more technical expertise.[Footnote] This highlights the prevalent skills gap concerning companies, not to mention the reason why they’re not making the impact they hope on the market.</p>

<p>But how do you fair in the technical world? Here are the areas you need to consider.</p>

<p><img src="http://techhamlet.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/05/technology-550x385.jpg" alt="Technology" /> <em>Image source : <a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/pennstatelive/6680713953/">Penn State</a></em></p>

<h3>Cloud hosting</h3>

<p>A phrase that continues to crop up within the business world is cloud hosting. Allowing you to take control of your server, cloud hosting provides access to a virtual server in which previously stored software is held. In most case scenarios, only a small percentage of business servers are actually being used at one given time, wasting both money and resource. This is where cloud hosting helps. Enabling you to turn your virtual server on and off when you need to, your business  could really start to save money in the long run.</p>

<h3>Mobility</h3>

<p>Separate from business environments, it’s clear to see that modern society it getting mobile. From the incorporation of iPads within the workplace to the mass use of smartphones, mobility has proved to be indispensable when it comes to company success. In addition to wireless connections such as the previous, it’s also important that you evolve with other technologies. Invest in Business Grade features, and ensure that employees are comfortable in working with technologies such as fixed lines and data services.</p>

<h3>Connectivity</h3>

<p>Whilst the previous two areas can’t be ignored, at the same time it’s vital for businesses to maintain traditional means of communication, and to do this you need the best connectivity. The fact is, the internet is continually changing, so in order to keep ahead of the curve, you need to look to services that will increase its productivity even further. For example, products such as business broadband and Ethernet are simple ways to get your SME up to speed and performing to the highest quality.</p>

<p>1 Geared for Growth White Paper- <a href="http://www.talktalkbusiness.co.uk/Global/Final-Assets/Collateral/white_papers/Geared%20for%20Growth%20-%20Report.pdf">http://www.talktalkbusiness.co.uk/Global/Final-Assets/Collateral/white_papers/Geared%20for%20Growth%20-%20Report.pdf</a></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Are Desktop Computers A Dying Tech?]]></title>
    <link href="http://techhamlet.com/2013/05/are-desktop-computers-a-dying-tech/"/>
    <updated>2013-05-30T08:25:45+05:30</updated>
    <id>http://techhamlet.com/2013/05/are-desktop-computers-a-dying-tech</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>With smart phones and tablets top of consumer wish lists, the decline of desktop computers has spiked since the turn of the year. We all thought it was a slow drop but it’s actually faster than anyone educated guesses. Sales have taken a 14% hit, so that’s it right? The desktop is dying?</p>

<p><img src="http://techhamlet.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/05/desktop-computer-550x366.jpg" alt="Desktop Computers" /> <em>Image source : <a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/27745117@N00/4319320763/">Hannaford</a></em></p>

<h3>The competition</h3>

<p>In 2013, tablets are due to outsell laptops for the first time in history. Not surprising as they can do both jobs and the desktop is clinging on for dear life. It is the transition to mobile devices that PC developers haven’t been able to understand or leverage. In fact, Windows 8 will probably be remembered as one of the final nails in the coffin of the desktop.</p>

<h3>The problem with Windows 8</h3>

<p>In a desperate effort to join the mobile revolution, radical changes were made as Windows looked to introduce touch base and remove the familiar start button. But, why would a consumer buy an expensive computer when a tablet is sufficient for many of the tasks they will be working on?</p>

<h3>Living together</h3>

<p>While it is obvious that tablets are the main reason for this decline, can we really do everything from there? Sophisticated keyboards mean that emails and even documents can be done on tablets and wireless printers mean we can get copies from anywhere, but there are still more creative, heavy and administrative tasks that we need a PC for. The experts believe that PCs won’t completely disappear but they need to get to flatline point where tablets are the primary consumption and PCs find their market as a shared heavy duty option in some homes – probably significantly cheaper.</p>

<h3>Who’s still buying desktop computers?</h3>

<p>Much like horse and cart to cars between the late 19th and early 20th centuries, desktops and tablets will have a turbulent relationship until ultimately both shares improve in value. Right now it’s quality over quantity for the desktop buyers with people wanting specialist gear for gaming, web development etc.</p>

<h3>Vision for desktops</h3>

<p>If you’re going to <a href="http://www.musicmagpie.co.uk/sell-my-laptop/index_laptop.asp">sell your laptop for cash</a>, it shouldn’t be for a desktop because it is a state of flux that might last for months or years yet. Major efforts need to be made in bringing them to the fore. Cases have to be revamped, towers need to be revitalised while monitors should always be as big as possible. It is all about which visionary can find a way to pair smartphones, tablets and desktops together in order to save and regenerate the market for desktops.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
