<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: others | Tech Hamlet]]></title>
  <link href="http://techhamlet.com/categories/others/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://techhamlet.com/"/>
  <updated>2014-01-02T18:19:51+05:30</updated>
  <id>http://techhamlet.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Pubudu Kodikara]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Wish You all a Very Happy New Year! How Did You Spent it?]]></title>
    <link href="http://techhamlet.com/2014/01/happy-new-year-2014/"/>
    <updated>2014-01-01T18:18:00+05:30</updated>
    <id>http://techhamlet.com/2014/01/happy-new-year-2014</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>We have just left 2013 and now stepping into 2014! Its a new year. Everyone have their own unique way to celebrate the new year. Make sure you spend it in a meaningful way...</p>

<p><img src="/images/post-images/2014/01/new-year-2014.jpg" alt="Happy New Year" /></p>

<p>You know what... Here's what I did for the new year... On the 31st of December, I took my phone, went to the balcony and started making a list...</p>

<p><a href="http://instagram.com/p/iVYZPaKogx/"><img src="/images/post-images/2014/01/my-balcony.jpg" alt="Thats my Balcony!" /></a></p>

<p>I listed all the mistakes I made in 2013. I wrote down how I am going to fix them! Then I set some goals for the upcoming year. When I'm done with the review, I went to bed!  In the morning, I woke up like a new born baby... I wanted to forget about the past and face the new year with a refreshed mind! You should not bring the past junk to the new year. Leave it behind. Only bring what you learnt from the past year. Make sure the new year is better than the past year!</p>

<p>What do you think? Isn't it a good way to face the new year? How did you spend it? Share with us!</p>

<p>We are now stepping into a brand new year... So, what kind of posts do you want from us this year? Let us know what you want and we shall give it to you!</p>

<h1>Happy New Year Everyone!</h1>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
